{
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks each . You will be awarded 2 marks for a correct answer. You may get 1 mark for showing a formal method. All other questions are worth 1 mark each . If you finish before the end, go back and check your work.Instructions You may not use a calculator to answer any questions in this test. S00080A0320  Page 04 of 20 1 979 + 100 =",
      "answer": "5 (error)"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "123 × 2 =",
      "answer": "5 (error)"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6.1 + 0.3 =",
      "answer": "Both clocks ticked, as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark S00080A0420  Page 05 of 20 4 24 × 3 =",
      "answer": "5  1"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "1,034 + 586 =",
      "answer": "Numbers in order, as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "48 ÷ 6 =",
      "answer": "Diagram completed correctly as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark S00080A0520  Page 06 of 20 7 472 − 9 =",
      "answer": "5  1"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2.5 + 0.05 =",
      "answer": "Numbers circled as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "5 × 4 × 7 =",
      "answer": "+ 68"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "| 15 =",
      "answer": "Numbers in order, as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 11,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "630 ÷ 9 =",
      "answer": "568 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 12,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "1.28 × 100 =",
      "answer": "The triangle has moved    6   squares to the  right"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark S00080A0720  Page 08 of 20 13 42 =",
      "answer": "5  1"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 14,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "50,000 − 500 =",
      "answer": "24 AND 48 only 1m Numbers may be given in either order."
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 15,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "100 × 100 =",
      "answer": "162 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark S00080A0820  Page 09 of 20 16 1,440 ÷ 12 =",
      "answer": "5  1"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 17,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "20% of 1,500 =",
      "answer": "× 326 = 5542 so all you need to do"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 18,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "1.52 × 6 =",
      "answer": "20 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 49 =",
      "answer": "+ 68"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 20,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "5,756 + 8,643 =",
      "answer": "( −10, −40 ) 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 21,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "7,505 } 5 =",
      "answer": "An explanation that shows that 5,868 can be made by adding 326 to 17 × 326, e.g."
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark S00080A1020  Page 11 of 20 22 12 − 6.01 =",
      "answer": "5  1"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks 54 × 23 Show your method S00080A1120  Page 12 of 20 24 15.4 − 8.88 =",
      "answer": "5 (error)"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 18 =",
      "answer": "459 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 27,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "95% of 240 =",
      "answer": "1"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 28,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "234,897 | 45,996 =",
      "answer": "6C7b"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks 678 × 54 Show your method",
      "answer": "5 (error)"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 30,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "17 × 11",
      "answer": "6C7a"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "=",
      "answer": "5 (error)"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark S00080A1420  Page 15 of 20 31 20 − 4 × 2 =",
      "answer": "5  1"
    },
    {
      "id": 31,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 2 =",
      "answer": "Numbers in order, as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 32,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 33,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "115 − 14 =",
      "answer": "6F5b"
    },
    {
      "id": 33,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 78 =",
      "answer": "459 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 34,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 2 =",
      "answer": "459 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 35,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark S00080A1720  Page 18 of 20 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. S00080A1820  Page 19 of 20 [BLANK PAGE] Please do not write on this page. S00080A1920  Sample key stage 2 mathematics paper 1: arithmetic Electronic PDF version product code: STA/15/7322/e   ISBN: 978-1-78315-740-2 For more copies Additional printed copies of this booklet are not available. It can be downloaded from www.gov.uk/government/publications. © Crown copyright and Crown information 2015 Re-use of Crown copyright and Crown information in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright or Crown information and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains public sector information licensed under the Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2016 sample tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "5  1"
    },
    {
      "id": 36,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 511,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals",
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "499 502 555 455 Write the number closest to 500 Write the number furthest from 500 1M003122_closer  –  29 September 2015 10:18 AM – Version 6 KS2 item template version 1.13N2a 4N4b 1 mark 1 mark M003122 E00070A0424 Page 5 of 24 2 £135,300A £131,500D£119,125B £91,500E£130,500C Put these houses in order of price starting with the lowest price. One has been done for you. B lowest 1 mark M003919M003919_housesale  –  6 October 2015 12:24 PM – Version 7 KS2 item template version 1.15N2 E00070A0524 Page 6 of 24 Write the three missing digits to make this addition correct. 1 5 +4 4 1 53 2 marks M003167M003167_add-on  –  20 October 2015 1:24 PM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.13C2 5C1 E00070A0624 Page 7 of 24   This table shows the number of people living in various towns in England. Town Population Bedford 82,448 Carlton 48,493 Dover 34,087 Formby 24,478 Telford 166,640 What is the total of the numbers of people living in Formby and  in Telford? What is the difference between the numbers of people living  in Bedford and in Dover? 4 1 mark 1 mark M003326M003326_Population increase  –  8 December 2015 1:32 PM – Version 6 KS2 item template version 1.14S1 6N5 E00070A0724 Page 8 of 24 5 Write each number in its correct place on the diagram.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 37,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 16,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Money",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "17   18   19 prime numbers square numbers even numbers 2 marks M004364M004364_invenntive a  –  29 September 2015 10:28 AM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.15C5 E00070A0824 Page 9 of 24  This diagram shows a shaded shape inside a border of squares. Draw the reflection of the shape in the mirror line. Use a ruler. mirror line6 1 mark M003259M003259_searchlight  –  29 September 2015 10:30 AM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.14G2c/5P2 E00070A0924 Page 10 of 24 Write the two missing values to make these equivalent fractions correct. =8 =4 3 12 7 1 mark 1 mark M004007M004007_fracking  –  29 September 2015 10:32 AM – Version 7 KS2 item template version 1.16F2 6A4 Circle two numbers that add together to equal 0.25 0.05   0.23   0.2   0.58 1 mark M003197M003197_quarterish  –  29 September 2015 10:33 AM – Version 2 KS2 item template version 1.15F10 E00070A01024 Page 11 of 24   6 pencils cost £1.68",
      "answer": "42.294 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 38,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Addition",
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals",
        "Money",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "pencils and 1 rubber cost £1.09 What is the cost of 1 rubber? Show your method9 2 marks M003185M003185_Pencils and Rubber  –  3 November 2015 9:33 AM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.13M9a E00070A01124 Page 12 of 24  Each diagram below is divided into equal sections. Shade three-quarters of each diagram. 10 2 marks M004010M004010_stealthy  –  1 October 2015 12:35 PM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.13F2 E00070A01224 Page 13 of 24 11  A packet contains 1.5 kg of oats. oats 1.5  kg Every day Maria uses 50 g of oats to make porridge. How many days does the packet of oats last? Show your method days 2 marks M004083M004083_fletcher  –  3 November 2015 9:48 AM – Version 3 KS2 item template version 1.15M9 E00070A01324 Page 14 of 24 12  n = 22 What is 2 n + 9? 2q + 4 = 100 Work out the value of q. q = 1 mark 1 mark M003963M003963_grouper  –  3 November 2015 10:09 AM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.16A2 E00070A01424 Page 15 of 24 13  A stack of 20 identical boxes is 140 cm tall. 140 cmNot actual  size Stefan takes three boxes off the top. How tall is the stack now? Show your method cm 2 marks M004020M004020_boxic  –  1 October 2015 12:38 PM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.16R1 E00070A01524 Page 16 of 24 Write all the common multiples of 3 and 8 that are less than 50 14 1 mark M004000M004000_three eights  –  1 October 2015 12:39 PM – Version 3 KS2 item template version 1.16C5 E00070A01624 Page 17 of 24   This thermometer shows temperatures in both °C and °F. –10 1440 30 20 10 0104 86 68 50 32°C °F Work out what 25 °C is in °F. Show your method °F15 2 marks M003202M003202_Very Cold  –  3 November 2015 10:18 AM – Version 2 KS2 item template version 1.15M5 E00070A01724 Page 18 of 24 Write the number that is five less than ten million. Write the number that is one hundred thousand less than six million. 16 1 mark 1 mark M003992M003992_big ones  –  29 September 2015 10:50 AM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.16N2 E00070A01824 Page 19 of 24 Calculate the size of angles a and b in this diagram. b a 160˚Not toscale a = ° b = °17 1 mark 1 mark M004040M004040_scissorhands  –  7 January 2016 1:54 PM – Version 6 KS2 item template version 1.16G4b 6G4a",
      "answer": "Both clocks ticked, as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 39,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 18,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals",
        "Money",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Write the missing number. 70 ÷ = 3.5 1 mark M003220M003220_Divide  –  1 October 2015 12:41 PM – Version 3 KS2 item template version 1.16C8 E00070A01924 Page 20 of 24 19   Miss Mills is making jam to sell at the school fair. Strawberries cost £7.50 per kg.   Sugar costs 79p per kg.   10 glass jars cost £6.90  She uses 12 kg of strawberries and 10 kg of sugar to  make 20 jars full of jam. Calculate the total cost to make 20 jars full of jam. Show your method £ 3 marks M005186M005186_jammie  –  3 November 2015 10:32 AM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.16C8 6A1 E00070A02024 Page 21 of 24 20  Here are two triangles drawn on coordinate axes. (_10, 40) (10, 10)(20, 30)y x 0A B Triangle B is a reflection of triangle A in the x-axis. Two of the new vertices of triangle B are (10, –10) and (20, –30). What are the coordinates of the third vertex of triangle B? (            ,            ) 1 mark M003924M003924_x-flector  –  10 November 2015 9:56 AM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.16P2 6P3 E00070A02124 Page 22 of 24 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. E00070A02224 Page 23 of 24 [BLANK PAGE] Please do not write on this page. E00070A02324",
      "answer": "20 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 40,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2016,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 2: reasoning Print version product code: STA/16/7376/p   ISBN: 978-1-78315-933-8 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/16/7376/e   ISBN: 978-1-78315-934-5 For more copies Additional printed copies of this booklet are not available. It can be downloaded from www.gov.uk/government/publications. © Crown copyright and Crown information 2016 Re-use of Crown copyright and Crown information in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright or Crown information and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains public sector information licensed under the Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2016 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 41,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 82,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Addition",
        "Decimals",
        "Time",
        "Money",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "96 124    138 2 marks M003127M003127_pimpernel  –  29 September 2015 11:43 AM – Version 2 KS2 item template version 1.13C1 E00080A0424 Page 5 of 24  This table shows the temperature at 9am on three days in January. 1st January 8th January 15th January + 5°C – 4°C + 1°C What is the difference between the temperature on 1st January and the temperature on 8th January? °C On 22nd January the temperature was 7 degrees lower than on  15th January. What was the temperature on 22nd January? °C 2 1 mark 1 mark M003997M003997_tempo  –  29 September 2015 11:45 AM – Version 6 KS2 item template version 1.16N5 3S1 E00080A0524 Page 6 of 24  A clock shows this time twice a day. 12 61 3 911 10 2 8 4 5 7 Tick the two digital clocks that show this time. 03:45 02:45 09:45 21:45 14:453 1 mark M004027M004027_digilogue  –  5 November 2015 10:26 AM – Version 3 KS2 item template version 1.14M4b E00080A0624 Page 7 of 24  Each shape stands for a number. Total 96Total 1 00 Work out the value of each shape. = = 4 1 mark 1 mark M003162M003162_Missing total  –  1 October 2015 1:02 PM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.16A2 E00080A0724 Page 8 of 24 Write these numbers in order, starting with the smallest. 0.78 0.607 5.6 0.098 4.003 smallest5 1 mark M004014M004014_disorderly  –  29 September 2015 11:52 AM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.15F8 E00080A0824 Page 9 of 24   Jacob cuts 4 metres of ribbon into three pieces. The length of the first piece is 1.28 metres. The length of the second piece is 1.65 metres. Work out the length of the third piece. Show your method metres6 2 marks M003179M003179_material  –  3 November 2015 10:45 AM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.14F10b 5M9b E00080A0924 Page 10 of 24  Here are five angles marked on a grid of squares. adb c e Write the letters of the angles that are obtuse. Write the letters of the angles that are acute. 7 1 mark 1 mark M004041M004041_ticker  –  1 October 2015 1:03 PM – Version 7 KS2 item template version 1.14G4 E00080A01024 Page 11 of 24 8  Olivia buys three packets of nuts. She pays with a £2 coin. This is her change. What is the cost of one packet of nuts? Show your method 2 marks M003172M003172_squirrel  –  29 September 2015 11:58 AM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.16C8 E00080A01124 Page 12 of 24   Here is part of the bus timetable from Riverdale to Mott Haven. Riverdale 10:02 10:12 10:31 10:48 Kingsbridge 10:11 10:21 10:38 10:55 Fordham 10:28 10:38 10:54 11:11 Tremont 10:36 10:44 11:00 11:17 Mott Haven 10:53 11:01 11:17 11:34 How many minutes does it take the 10:31 bus from Riverdale to reach Mott Haven? minutes Mr Evans is at Fordham at 10:30 What is the earliest time he can reach Tremont on the bus? 9 1 mark 1 mark M004042M004042_mottzarella  –  29 September 2015 12:00 PM – Version 7 KS2 item template version 1.15S1 E00080A01224 Page 13 of 24 10  Emma makes a cuboid using 12 cubes. Write the letter of the cuboid that has a different volume from Emma’s cuboid. AB C DE M003933_dozen’t  –  1 October 2015 1:03 PM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.15M8 1 mark M003933 E00080A01324 Page 14 of 24 11   A toy shop orders 11 boxes of marbles. Each box contains 6 bags of marbles.  Each bag contains 45 marbles. How many marbles does the shop order in total? Show your method marbles 2 marks M005160 M005160_Egghead  –  1 October 2015 1:04 PM – Version 3 KS2 item template version 1.15C8a 5C7a E00080A01424 Page 15 of 24 12  A triangle is translated from position A to position B. A B Complete the sentence. The triangle has moved squares to the right and squares down. 1 mark M003966M003966_transition  –  6 October 2015 12:59 PM – Version 7 KS2 item template version 1.14P2 E00080A01524 Page 16 of 24   Lara chooses a number less than 20 She divides it by 2 and then adds 6  She then divides this result by 3  Her answer is 4.5 What was the number she started with? Show your method13 2 marks M003988M003988_crofter  –  1 October 2015 1:05 PM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.15F10 E00080A01624 Page 17 of 24 Complete each sentence using a number from the list below.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 42,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 120,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "240 600 1,440 3,600 6,000 There are seconds in an hour. There are minutes in a day.14 1 mark 1 mark M003990M003990_hard times  –  6 October 2015 1:01 PM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.16M5d 6C6 Complete this table by rounding the numbers to the nearest hundred. Rounded to the nearest hundred 20,906 2,090.6 209.0615 2 marks M003237M003237_round table  –  8 December 2015 1:50 PM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.15N4 6N4 E00080A01724 Page 18 of 24  6 small bricks have the same mass as 5 large bricks. The mass of one small brick is 2.5 kg. What is the mass of one large brick? Show your method kg16 2 marks M004019M004019_brickston  –  1 October 2015 1:07 PM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.16R4 E00080A01824 Page 19 of 24  Here are five triangles on a square grid. A B D EC Four of the triangles have the same area. Which triangle has a different area? 17 1 mark M003985M003985_axehead  –  8 December 2015 4:29 PM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.16M7b E00080A01924 Page 20 of 24 18  The diagonals of this quadrilateral cross at right angles. Tick all the quadrilaterals that have diagonals which cross at right angles.M003947_diagnosis  –  17 December 2015 3:20 PM – Version 4 KS2 item template version 1.16G2c 2 marks M003947 E00080A02024 Page 21 of 24 Circle two numbers that multiply together to equal 1 million.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 43,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 200,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals",
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2,000   5,000   50,00019 1 mark M003234M003234_millionista  –  6 October 2015 1:05 PM – Version 2 KS2 item template version 1.16N6 6C8 Lara had some money.  She spent £1.25 on a drink.  She spent £1.60 on a sandwich.  She has three-quarters of her money left. How much money did Lara have to start with? Show your method £20 2 marks M003213M003213_spender  –  1 October 2015 1:09 PM – Version 3 KS2 item template version 1.15f10 5M9a E00080A02124 Page 22 of 24 1 mark M003683M003683  –  6 October 2015 1:07 PM – Version 3",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 44,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 21,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "5,542  ÷  17  =  326 Explain how you can use this fact to find the answer to 18 × 326 KS2 item template version 1.1E00080A02224 Page 23 of 24 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. E00080A02324",
      "answer": "An explanation that shows that 5,868 can be made by adding 326 to 17 × 326, e.g."
    },
    {
      "id": 45,
      "year": 2016,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2016,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 3: reasoning Print version product code: STA/16/7377/p   ISBN: 978-1-78315-935-2 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/16/7377/e   ISBN: 978-1-78315-936-9 For more copies Additional printed copies of this booklet are not available. It can be downloaded from www.gov.uk/government/publications. © Crown copyright and Crown information 2016 Re-use of Crown copyright and Crown information in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright or Crown information and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains public sector information licensed under the Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2016 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 46,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "40 + 1,000 =",
      "answer": "10 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 47,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "707 + 1,818 =",
      "answer": "5 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 48,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 36 =",
      "answer": "The correct time circled as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 49,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "505 ÷ 1 =",
      "answer": "+ 16 ="
    },
    {
      "id": 50,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "345 − 60 =",
      "answer": "£ 302.27 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 51,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2.7 + 3.014 =",
      "answer": "The correct time circled as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 52,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 4,500 + 600",
      "answer": "Triangle with vertices at (2,1) AND (2,4) AND (5,1) drawn on the grid as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 53,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "8 × 33 =",
      "answer": "264 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 54,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "72 ÷ 9 =",
      "answer": "+ 13 =22"
    },
    {
      "id": 55,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "167 × 4 =",
      "answer": "as an equivalent to 14 in an"
    },
    {
      "id": 56,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 11,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "4,912 − 824 =",
      "answer": "32 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 57,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 100,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 38",
      "answer": "km is 5  cm"
    },
    {
      "id": 58,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 100,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "=",
      "answer": "km is 5  cm"
    },
    {
      "id": 59,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 13,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 100 = 1,059",
      "answer": "1,159 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 60,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 14,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "50 + (36 ÷ 6) =",
      "answer": "56 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 61,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 35 =",
      "answer": "The correct time circled as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 62,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 16,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "30 × 40 =",
      "answer": "540 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 63,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 17,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "581 ÷ 7 =",
      "answer": "Quadrilateral completed as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 64,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 18,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "0.04 ÷ 10 =",
      "answer": "Both numbers correct as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 65,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 19,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2,345 × 1,000 =",
      "answer": "2,345,000 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 66,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 21,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "9 − 3.45 =",
      "answer": "1.2"
    },
    {
      "id": 67,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks 4 7 8 1 × 2 3 Show your method F00060A01120  Page 12 of 20 KS2 item arithmetic template version 1.0M005617  –  25 October 2016 4:13 PM – Version 1 233",
      "answer": "5 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 68,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 38 =",
      "answer": "+ 16 ="
    },
    {
      "id": 69,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks 4 1 8 × 4 6 Show your method F00060A01220  Page 13 of 20 KS2 item arithmetic template version 1.0M005552  –  25 October 2016 2:48 PM – Version 1",
      "answer": "5 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 70,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 25,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "37.8 − 14.671 =",
      "answer": "23.129 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 71,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 15 + 1",
      "answer": "+ 16 ="
    },
    {
      "id": 72,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "=",
      "answer": "as an equivalent to 14 in an"
    },
    {
      "id": 73,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2745,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 4 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 74,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 2 =",
      "answer": "264 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 75,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 29,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "45% of 460 =",
      "answer": "6R2"
    },
    {
      "id": 76,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 30213,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 56 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 77,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 31,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "7% of 500 =",
      "answer": "1"
    },
    {
      "id": 78,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 18 =",
      "answer": "The correct time circled as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 79,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 33,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "0.9 × 200 =",
      "answer": "180 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 80,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 34,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "15% × 1,000 =",
      "answer": "+ w = 27 + w + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 81,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 57 =",
      "answer": "5 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 82,
      "year": 2017,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2017,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 1: arithmetic Print version product code: STA/17/7736/p   ISBN: 978-1-78644-275-8 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/17/7736/e   ISBN: 978-1-78644-295-6 For more copies Additional printed copies of this booklet are not available. It can be downloaded from www.gov.uk/government/publications. © Crown copyright and Crown information 2017 Re-use of Crown copyright and Crown information in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright or Crown information and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains public sector information licensed under the Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2017 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 83,
      "year": 2018,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2018,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Percentages",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Key stage 2 mathematics test The key stage 2 mathematics test consists of 3 papers. The papers must be administered in order. Pupils can have a break between Paper 1 and Paper 2. Test packs must not be opened until the pupils are in the test room ready to complete the test, unless early opening is required to meet individual pupils’ needs. The scheduled day for the administration of Papers 1 and 2 is Wednesday 16 May. The scheduled day for the administration of Paper 3 is Thursday 17 May. Paper 1: arithmetic The following information explains how to administer the key stage 2 mathematics test Paper 1: arithmetic. If you have any questions, you should check with your headteacher or key stage 2 test co-ordinator before you administer the test. Please follow these instructions correctly to ensure that the test is properly administered. Failure to administer the test correctly could result in a maladministration investigation. Format • Paper 1: arithmetic consists of a single test paper. • Pupils will have 30 minutes to complete Paper 1 by answering the questions in the test paper. Equipment Each pupil will need the equipment specified below: • a blue / black pen or a dark pencil• ruler. Rubbers are allowed, but please encourage pupils to cross out answers they wish to change instead of rubbing them out. Pupils are not allowed: • calculators • squared paper• tracing paper• other mathematical equipment, such as angle measurers or mirrors. Assistance • You must ensure that nothing you say or do during the test could be interpreted as giving pupils an advantage, e.g. indicating that an answer is correct or incorrect, or suggesting the pupil looks at an answer again. • If a pupil requests it, a question may be read to the pupil on a one-to-one basis. • If reading to a pupil, you can read words and numbers but not mathematical symbols. This is to ensure that pupils are not given an unfair advantage by having the function inadvertently explained by reading its name. • There is no specific hearing impairment guidance for this test, but be careful when signing numbers, mathematical signs and words. Ensure you do not convey information that would give pupils an advantage. • Guidance for administering the test to pupils with a visual impairment is contained in the modified test packs. • The example below illustrates how to deal with a common situation. Q.  Do I need to multiply when I calculate 95% of 240? A.  I can’t tell you, but think hard and try to remember.  We can talk about it after the test. Before the test begins• Review the list of pupils with any particular individual needs, e.g. pupils who are allowed additional time, who need support from a scribe or reader or who may need a transcript made at the end of the test. • Ensure that you know how to administer any access arrangements correctly by referring to the 2018 key stage 2 access arrangements guidance. • It is important that the pupils’ names on their tests match the names on the test attendance register. Check with your test co-ordinator whether any pupil in your group is known by a different name in school, or has changed their name since pupil registration. This is so you can remind the pupil to write the correct name on their test paper. Before the test begins (continued)• Check that there are enough administrators to maintain adequate supervision during the test. You should consider the possibility that at least one test administrator might need to leave the room with a pupil. • Ensure that you understand how to deal with issues during the tests. • Write the school’s name and DfE number on a board that is visible to all pupils. • Leave space on the board to write the start and finish times of the test. What to do at the start of the test• Check that seating is appropriately spaced and that no pupil can see another pupil’s test paper.• Check that pupils don’t have mobile phones or other disruptive items. • Check that pupils don’t have any materials or equipment that may give them extra help. • Ensure that each pupil has a copy of Paper 1: arithmetic. • Write the start and finish times on the board so that all pupils can see them. How to introduce the testIt is important to brief pupils fully at the start of each test. You should use this script to introduce Paper 1: arithmetic. This is the key stage 2 mathematics Paper 1: arithmetic. You should have Paper 1: arithmetic  in front of you. You will need a blue or black pen or dark pencil. Write your name, school name and DfE number on the front of your test paper. [If any pupil’s name differs from the name provided during pupil registration, instruct the pupil to write both names on the paper.] Open your test paper to page 3. I will read the instructions to you. You must not use a calculator to answer any questions in this test.You have 30 minutes to complete this test. Work as quickly and as carefully as you can. Put your answer in the box for each question. All answers should be given as a single value.For questions expressed as common fractions or mixed numbers, you should give your answers as common fractions or mixed numbers. If you cannot do a question, go on to the next one. You can come back to it later if you have time. If you finish before the end, go back and check your work. The number under each box at the side of the page tells you the number of marks available for each question. In this test, long division and long multiplication questions are worth 2 marks each.  You will be awarded 2 marks for a correct answer. You may get 1 mark for showing a formal method. All other questions are worth 1 mark each. To make sure your answers can be marked, don’t write in the grey areas, on the barcode or on the lines at the top and bottom or the edge of the page and don’t crumple your test paper. If you want to change your answer, put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read. If you have to use a rubber, make sure you rub out your answer completely before writing a new one. Remember to check your work carefully. If you have any questions during the test, you should put your hand up and wait for someone to come to you. Remember, I can’t help you to answer any of the test questions. You must not talk to each other. Are there any questions you want to ask me now? I will tell you when you have 5 minutes left. I will tell you when the test is over and to stop writing. You may now start the test.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 84,
      "year": 2018,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2018,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Administering Paper 1: arithmetic Print version product code: STA/18/8053/p     ISBN: 978-1-78644-723-4 Electronic version product code: STA/18/8053/e     ISBN: 978-1-78644-736-4 © Crown copyright 2018 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may  re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence . When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2018 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Where we have identified any third-party copyright information you will need to obtain permission from the copyright holders concerned.How to deal with issues during the testIt is impossible to plan for every scenario. Whatever action you take, pupil safety must always be your first consideration. In the following circumstances, you will need to stop the test either for an individual pupil or for the whole cohort: • test papers are incorrectly collated or the print is illegible • an incorrect test has been administered • a fire alarm goes off • a pupil is unwell • a pupil needs to leave the room • a pupil is caught cheating. If you need to stop the test: • make a note of the time • make sure pupils are kept under test conditions and that they are supervised • if pupils have to leave the room, ensure they don’t talk about the test • speak to your test co-ordinator or a senior member of staff for advice about what to do next• consider contacting the national curriculum assessments helpline on 0300 303 3013 for further advice. You should brief your headteacher on how the incident was dealt with once the test is over. What to do at the end of the test• If you need to make a transcript of a test script, complete it with the individual pupil at the end of the test, under test conditions. Particular care should be taken to ensure accurate transcriptions are made and pupils’ answers are not corrected or amended. • Ensure that you inform your senior member of staff / test co-ordinator if you have made a transcript, or if a pupil has used a scribe, word processor or other electronic or technical device. This is so that they can complete the appropriate online notification. • Make sure you have collected every test script. Return them immediately to the senior member of staff who is responsible for collating the tests. • Do not look at, review or amend pupils’ answers in any way (unless it is necessary to make a transcript). If you tamper with or make changes to pupils’ answers, it will be considered maladministration and results could be annulled. • Do not keep or photocopy test scripts for any reason.• Ensure that any unused test materials are stored securely until Friday 25 May 2018.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 85,
      "year": 2018,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "copies of Paper 2: reasoningThis pack must be kept secure and unopened until the start of the test on Wednesday 16 May 2018. Early opening, up to 1 hour before the test starts, is only allowed if access to the contents is needed to make adaptations to meet individual pupils’ needs. Early opening of more than 1 hour is only allowed if permission has been granted by STA. Please ensure you have read and understood the 2018 test administration guidance before opening this pack.CONFIDENTIAL",
      "answer": "308 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 86,
      "year": 2018,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2018,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Key stage 2 mathematics test The key stage 2 mathematics test consists of 3 papers. The papers must be administered in order. Pupils can have a break between Paper 1 and Paper 2. Test packs must not be opened until the pupils are in the test room ready to complete the test, unless early opening is required to meet individual pupils’ needs. The scheduled day for the administration of Papers 1 and 2 is Wednesday 16 May. The scheduled day for the administration of Paper 3 is Thursday 17 May. Paper 2: reasoning The following information explains how to administer the key stage 2 mathematics test Paper 2: reasoning. If you have any questions, you should check with your headteacher or key stage 2 test co-ordinator before you administer the test. Please follow these instructions correctly to ensure that the test is properly administered. Failure to administer the test correctly could result in a maladministration investigation. Format • Paper 2: reasoning consists of a single test paper. • Pupils will have 40 minutes to complete Paper 2 by answering the questions in the test paper. Equipment Each pupil will need the equipment specified below: • a blue / black pen or a dark pencil • a sharp, dark pencil for mathematical drawing • a ruler (showing centimetres and millimetres) • an angle measurer or protractor (papers 2 and 3 only)• a mirror (papers 2 and 3 only). Rubbers are allowed, but please encourage pupils to cross out answers they wish to change instead of rubbing them out. Pupils may use the following equipment, if this is normal classroom practice: • monolingual English electronic spell checkers• bilingual word lists • bilingual dictionaries or electronic translators , provided they only give word-for-word translations . Pupils are not allowed: • calculators • squared paper• tracing paper. Assistance • You must ensure that nothing you say or do during the test could be interpreted as giving pupils an advantage, e.g. indicating that an answer is correct or incorrect, or suggesting the pupil looks at an answer again. • If a pupil requests it, a question may be read to the pupil on a one-to-one basis. • If reading to a pupil, you can read words and numbers but not mathematical symbols. This is to ensure that pupils are not given an unfair advantage by having the function inadvertently explained by reading its name. • For pupils with hearing impairment, be careful when signing numbers, mathematical signs and words. In particular, be careful when signing the following: Q10: > = < You may point to the signs. Take care not to explain what each sign means. Q11: faces, vertices, edges Q12: volume Take care not to indicate how volume of a shape is calculated i.e. height multiplied by width multiplied by depth. • Guidance for administering the test to pupils with a visual impairment is contained in the modified test packs. • At a pupil’s request, you may point to parts of the test paper such as charts, diagrams, statements and equations, but you must not explain the information or help the pupil by interpreting it. • The examples below illustrate how to deal with some common situations. Q. What does ‘quadrilateral’ or ‘>’ or ‘<’ mean?  A. I can’t tell you, but think hard and try to remember. We can talk about it after the test. Q. What is ‘0.6’? A. That’s nought point six. Assistance (continued)• You must not explain any subject-specific terminology. If any other word in a question is unfamiliar to pupils, you may explain it, or show them objects or pictures to help them understand . Before the test begins • Review the list of pupils with any particular individual needs, e.g. pupils who are allowed additional time, who need support from a scribe or reader or who may need a transcript made at the end of the test. • Ensure that you know how to administer any access arrangements correctly by referring to the 2018 key stage 2 access arrangements guidance. • It is important that the pupils’ names on their tests match the names on the test attendance register. Check with your test co-ordinator whether any pupil in your group is known by a different name in school, or has changed their name since pupil registration. This is so you can remind the pupil to write the correct name on their test paper. • Check that there are enough administrators to maintain adequate supervision during the test. You should consider the possibility that at least one test administrator might need to leave the room with a pupil. • Ensure that you understand how to deal with issues during the tests. • Write the school’s name and DfE number on a board that is visible to all pupils. • Leave space on the board to write the start and finish times of the test. What to do at the start of the test • Check that seating is appropriately spaced and that no pupil can see another pupil’s test paper. • Check that pupils don’t have mobile phones or other disruptive items. • Check that pupils don’t have any materials or equipment that may give them extra help. • Ensure that each pupil has a copy of Paper 2: reasoning. • Write the start and finish times on the board so that all pupils can see them. How to introduce the test (This section continues on the following page.)It is important to brief pupils fully at the start of each test. You should use this script to introduce mathematics Paper 2: reasoning. This is the key stage 2 mathematics Paper 2: reasoning. You should have Paper 2: reasoning in front of you. You will need a blue or black pen, a dark sharp pencil, a ruler, a protractor and a mirror. Write your name, school name and DfE number on the front of your test paper. [If any pupil’s name differs from the name provided during pupil registration, instruct the pupil to write both names on the paper.] Open your test paper to page 3. I will read the instructions to you. You must not use a calculator to answer any question in this test. You have 40 minutes to complete this test. Follow the instructions for each question. Work as quickly and as carefully as you can.If you need to do working out, you can use the space around the question. Do not write over any barcodes. Some questions have a method box. For these questions you may get a mark for showing your method. If you cannot do a question, go on to the next one.  You can come back to it later if you have time. If you finish before the end, go back and check your work. The number under each line at the side of the page tells you the number of marks available for each question. To make sure your answers can be marked, don’t write in the grey areas, on the barcode or on the lines at the top and bottom or the edge of the page and don’t crumple your test paper. If you want to change your answer, put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read. If you want to change a drawing, you should either put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read, or use a rubber. If you have to use a rubber, make sure you rub out your answer completely before writing a new one. Remember to check your work carefully. If you have any questions during the test, you should put your hand up and wait for someone to come to you. Remember, I can’t help you to answer any of the test questions.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 87,
      "year": 2018,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "copies of Paper 3: reasoningThis pack must be kept secure and unopened until the start of the test on Thursday 17 May 2018. Early opening, up to 1 hour before the test starts, is only allowed if access to the contents is needed to make adaptations to meet individual pupils’ needs. Early opening of more than 1 hour is only allowed if permission has been granted by STA. Please ensure you have read and understood the 2018 test administration guidance before opening this pack.CONFIDENTIAL",
      "answer": "308 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 88,
      "year": 2018,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2018,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Key stage 2 mathematics test The key stage 2 mathematics test consists of 3 papers. The papers must be administered in order. Test packs must not be opened until the pupils are in the test room ready to complete the test, unless early opening is required to meet individual pupils’ needs. The scheduled day for the administration of Paper 3 is Thursday 17 May. Paper 3: reasoning The following information explains how to administer the key stage 2 mathematics test Paper 3: reasoning. If you have any questions, you should check with your headteacher or key stage 2 test co-ordinator before you administer the test. Please follow these instructions correctly to ensure that the test is properly administered. Failure to administer the test correctly could result in a maladministration investigation. Format • Paper 3: reasoning consists of a single test paper. • Pupils will have 40 minutes to complete Paper 3 by answering the questions in the test paper. Equipment Each pupil will need the equipment specified below: • a blue / black pen or a dark pencil • a sharp, dark pencil for mathematical drawing • a ruler (showing centimetres and millimetres) • an angle measurer or protractor (papers 2 and 3 only)• a mirror (papers 2 and 3 only). Rubbers are allowed, but please encourage pupils to cross out answers they wish to change instead of rubbing them out. Pupils may use the following equipment, if this is normal classroom practice: • monolingual English electronic spell checkers• bilingual word lists • bilingual dictionaries or electronic translators , provided they only give word-for-word translations . Pupils are not allowed: • calculators • squared paper• tracing paper. Assistance • You must ensure that nothing you say or do during the test could be interpreted as giving pupils an advantage, e.g. indicating that an answer is correct or incorrect, or suggesting the pupil looks at an answer again. • If a pupil requests it, a question may be read to the pupil on a one-to-one basis. • If reading to a pupil, you can read words and numbers but not mathematical symbols. This is to ensure that pupils are not given an unfair advantage by having the function inadvertently explained by reading its name. • For pupils with hearing impairment, be careful when signing numbers, mathematical signs and words. In particular, be careful when signing the following: Q14: equilateral Take care not to indicate that an equilateral triangle has three equal sides or angles. • Guidance for administering the test to pupils with a visual impairment is contained in the modified test packs.• At a pupil’s request, you may point to parts of the test paper such as charts, diagrams, statements and equations, but you must not explain the information or help the pupil by interpreting it. • The examples below illustrate how to deal with some common situations. Q. What does ‘quadrilateral’ or ‘>’ or ‘<’ mean?  A. I can’t tell you, but think hard and try to remember. We can talk about it after the test. Q. What is ‘0.6’? A. That’s nought point six. • You must not explain any subject-specific terminology. If any other word in a question is unfamiliar to pupils, you may explain it, or show them objects or pictures to help them understand. Before the test begins• Review the list of pupils with any particular individual needs, e.g. pupils who are allowed additional time, who need support from a scribe or who may need a transcript made at the end of the test. • Ensure that you know how to administer any access arrangements correctly by referring to the 2018 key stage 2 access arrangements guidance. • It is important that the pupils’ names on their tests match the names on the test attendance register. Check with your test co-ordinator whether any pupil in your group is known by a different name in school, or has changed their name since pupil registration. This is so you can remind the pupil to write the correct name on their test paper. • Check that there are enough administrators to maintain adequate supervision during the test. You should consider the possibility that at least one test administrator might need to leave the room with a pupil. • Ensure that you understand how to deal with issues during the tests. • Write the school’s name and DfE number on a board that is visible to all pupils. • Leave space on the board to write the start and finish times of the test. What to do at the start of the test • Check that pupils don’t have mobile phones or other disruptive items. • Check that pupils don’t have any materials or equipment that may give them extra help. • Check that seating is appropriately spaced and that no pupil can see another pupil’s test paper. • Ensure that each pupil has a copy of Paper 3: reasoning. • Write the start and finish times on the board so that all pupils can see them. How to introduce the testIt is important to brief pupils fully at the start of each test. You should use this script to introduce mathematics Paper 3: reasoning. This is the key stage 2 mathematics Paper 3: reasoning. You should have Paper 3: reasoning  in front of you. You will need a blue or black pen, a dark sharp pencil, a ruler, a protractor and a mirror.    Write your name, school name and DfE number on the front of your test paper. [If any pupil’s name differs from the name provided during pupil registration, instruct the pupil to write both names on the paper.] Open your test paper to page 3. I will read the instructions to you. You must not use a calculator to answer any question in this test.You have 40 minutes to complete this test. Follow the instructions for each question.Work as quickly and as carefully as you can.If you need to do working out, you can use the space around the question. Do not write over any barcodes.Some questions have a method box. For these questions you may get a mark for showing your method. If you cannot do a question, go on to the next one.  You can come back to it later if you have time. If you finish before the end, go back and check your work. The number under each line at the side of the page tells you the number of marks available for each question. To make sure your answers can be marked, don’t write in the grey areas, on the barcode or on the lines at the top and bottom or the edge of the page and don’t crumple your test paper. If you want to change your answer, put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read. If you want to change a drawing, you should either put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read, or use a rubber. If you have to use a rubber, make sure you rub out your answer completely before writing a new one. Remember to check your work carefully. If you have any questions during the test, you should put your hand up and wait for someone to come to you. Remember, I can’t help you to answer any of the test questions. This section continues on the next page.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 89,
      "year": 2019,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2019,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Percentages",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Key stage 2 mathematics test The key stage 2 mathematics test consists of 3 papers. The papers must be administered in order. Pupils can have a break between Paper 1 and Paper 2. Test packs must not be opened until the pupils are in the test room ready to complete the test, unless early opening is required to meet individual pupils’ needs. The scheduled day for the administration of Papers 1 and 2 is Wednesday 15 May. The scheduled day for the administration of Paper 3 is Thursday 16 May. Paper 1: arithmetic The following information explains how to administer the key stage 2 mathematics test Paper 1: arithmetic. If you have any questions, you should check with your headteacher or key stage 2 test co-ordinator before you administer the test. Please follow these instructions correctly to ensure that the test is properly administered. Failure to administer the test correctly could result in a maladministration investigation. Format • Paper 1: arithmetic consists of a single test paper. • Pupils will have 30 minutes to complete Paper 1 by answering the questions in the test paper. Equipment Each pupil will need the equipment specified below: • a blue / black pen or a dark pencil• ruler. Rubbers are allowed, but please encourage pupils to cross out answers they wish to change instead of rubbing them out. Pupils are not allowed: • calculators • squared paper• tracing paper• other mathematical equipment, such as angle measurers or mirrors. Assistance • You must ensure that nothing you say or do during the test could be interpreted as giving pupils an advantage, e.g. indicating that an answer is correct or incorrect, or suggesting the pupil looks at an answer again. • If a pupil requests it, a question may be read to the pupil on a one-to-one basis. • If reading to a pupil, you can read words and numbers but not mathematical symbols. This is to ensure that pupils are not given an unfair advantage by having the function inadvertently explained by reading its name. • There is no specific hearing impairment guidance for this test, but be careful when signing numbers, mathematical signs and words. Ensure you do not convey information that would give pupils an advantage. • Guidance for administering the test to pupils with a visual impairment is contained in the modified test packs. • The example below illustrates how to deal with a common situation. Q.  Do I need to multiply when I calculate 95% of 240? A.  I can’t tell you, but think hard and try to remember.  We can talk about it after the test. Before the test begins• Review the list of pupils with any particular individual needs, e.g. pupils who are allowed additional time, who need support from a scribe or reader or who may need a transcript made at the end of the test. • It is important that the pupils’ names on their tests match the names on the test attendance register. Check with your test co-ordinator whether any pupil in your group is known by a different name in school, or has changed their name since pupil registration. This is so you can remind the pupil to write the correct name on their test paper. • Write the school’s name and DfE number on a board that is visible to all pupils. • Leave space on the board to write the start and finish times of the test. What to do at the start of the test• Check that seating is appropriately spaced and that no pupil can see another pupil’s test paper. • Check that pupils don’t have mobile phones or other disruptive items. • Check that pupils don’t have any materials or equipment that may give them extra help. • Ensure that each pupil has a copy of Paper 1: arithmetic. • Write the start and finish times on the board so that all pupils can see them. How to introduce the testIt is important to brief pupils fully at the start of each test. You should use this script to introduce Paper 1: arithmetic. This is the key stage 2 mathematics Paper 1: arithmetic. You should have Paper 1: arithmetic in front of you. You will need a blue or black pen or dark pencil and a ruler. Write your name, school name and DfE number on the front of your test paper. [If any pupil’s name differs from the name provided during pupil registration, instruct the pupil to write both names on the paper.] Open your test paper to page 3. I will read the instructions to you. You must not use a calculator to answer any questions in this test. You have 30 minutes to complete this test. Work as quickly and as carefully as you can. Put your answer in the box for each question.All answers should be given as a single value.For questions expressed as common fractions or mixed numbers, you should give your answers as common fractions or mixed numbers. If you cannot do a question, go on to the next one. You can come back to it later if you have time. If you finish before the end, go back and check your work. The number under each box at the side of the page tells you the number of marks available for each question. In this test, long division and long multiplication questions are worth 2 marks each.  You will be awarded 2 marks for a correct answer. You may get 1 mark for showing a formal method. All other questions are worth 1 mark each. To make sure your answers can be marked, don’t write in the grey areas, on the barcode or on the lines at the top and bottom or the edge of the page and don’t crumple your test paper. If you want to change your answer, put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read. If you have to use a rubber, make sure you rub out your answer completely before writing a new one. Remember to check your work carefully. If you have any questions during the test, you should put your hand up and wait for someone to come to you. Remember, I can’t help you to answer any of the test questions. You must not talk to each other. Are there any questions you want to ask me now? I will tell you when you have 5 minutes left. I will tell you when the test is over and to stop writing. You may now start the test. How to deal with issues during  the testIt is impossible to plan for every scenario. Whatever action you take, pupil safety must always be your first consideration. In the following circumstances, you will need to stop the test either for an individual pupil or for the whole cohort: • test papers are incorrectly collated or the print is illegible • an incorrect test has been administered • a fire alarm goes off • a pupil is unwell • a pupil needs to leave the room • a pupil is caught cheating. If you need to stop the test: • make a note of the time • make sure pupils are kept under test conditions and that they are supervised • if pupils have to leave the room, ensure they don’t talk about the test • speak to your test co-ordinator or a senior member of staff for advice about what to do next• consider contacting the national curriculum assessments helpline on 0300 303 3013 for further advice. You should brief your headteacher on how the incident was dealt with, once the test is over. What to do at the end  of the test• If you need to make a transcript of a test script, complete it with the individual pupil at the end of the test, under test conditions. Particular care should be taken to ensure accurate transcriptions are made and pupils’ answers are not corrected or amended. • Ensure that you inform your senior member of staff / test co-ordinator if you have made a transcript, or if a pupil has used a scribe, word processor or other electronic or technical device. This is so that they can complete the appropriate online notification. • Make sure you have collected every test script. Return them immediately to the senior member of staff who is responsible for collating the tests. • Do not look at, review or amend pupils’ answers in any way (unless it is necessary to make a transcript). If you tamper with or make changes to pupils’ answers, it will be considered maladministration and results could be annulled. • Do not keep or photocopy test scripts for any reason.• Ensure that any unused test materials are stored securely until Friday 24 May 2019.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 90,
      "year": 2019,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2019,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Administering Paper 1: arithmetic Print version product code: STA/19/8229/p     ISBN: 978-1-78957-132-5 Electronic version product code: STA/19/8229/e     ISBN: 978-1-78957-144-8 © Crown copyright 2019 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may  re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2019 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Where we have identified any third-party copyright information you will need to obtain permission from the copyright holders concerned.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 91,
      "year": 2019,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "copies of Paper 2: reasoningThis pack must be kept secure and unopened until the start of the test on Wednesday 15 May 2019. Early opening, up to 1 hour before the test starts, is only allowed if access to the contents is needed to make adaptations to meet individual pupils’ needs. Early opening of more than 1 hour is only allowed if permission has been granted by STA. Please ensure you have read and understood the 2019 test administration guidance before opening this pack. CONFIDENTIAL",
      "answer": "– a"
    },
    {
      "id": 92,
      "year": 2019,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2019,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Area",
        "Perimeter",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Key stage 2 mathematics test The key stage 2 mathematics test consists of 3 papers. The papers must be administered in order. Pupils can have a break between Paper 1 and Paper 2. Test packs must not be opened until the pupils are in the test room ready to complete the test, unless early opening is required to meet individual pupils’ needs. The scheduled day for the administration of Papers 1 and 2 is Wednesday 15 May. The scheduled day for the administration of Paper 3 is Thursday 16 May. Paper 2: reasoning The following information explains how to administer the key stage 2 mathematics test Paper 2: reasoning. If you have any questions, you should check with your headteacher or key stage 2 test co-ordinator before you administer the test. Please follow these instructions correctly to ensure that the test is properly administered. Failure to administer the test correctly could result in a maladministration investigation. Format • Paper 2: reasoning consists of a single test paper. • Pupils will have 40 minutes to complete Paper 2 by answering the questions in the test paper. Equipment Each pupil will need the equipment specified below: • a blue / black pen or a dark pencil • a sharp, dark pencil for mathematical drawing • a ruler (showing centimetres and millimetres) • an angle measurer or protractor (papers 2 and 3 only)• a mirror (papers 2 and 3 only). Rubbers are allowed, but please encourage pupils to cross out answers they wish to change instead of rubbing them out. Pupils may use the following equipment, if this is normal classroom practice: • monolingual English electronic spell checkers• bilingual word lists • bilingual dictionaries or electronic translators , provided they only give word-for-word translations . Pupils are not allowed: • calculators • squared paper• tracing paper. Assistance • You may use photocopying to enlarge pages from the test papers as part of the access arrangements for specific pupils. Please note that the given 8cm line in the following question should not be enlarged: Question 13 • You must ensure that nothing you say or do during the test could be interpreted as giving pupils an advantage, e.g. indicating that an answer is correct or incorrect, or suggesting the pupil looks at an answer again. • If a pupil requests it, a question may be read to the pupil on a one-to-one basis. • If reading to a pupil, you can read words and numbers but not mathematical symbols. This is to ensure that pupils are not given an unfair advantage by having the function inadvertently explained by reading its name. • For pupils with hearing impairment, be careful when signing numbers, mathematical signs and words. In particular, be careful when signing the following: Q12: You may indicate the three symbols, but do not explain the meaning of each symbol. Q17: perimeter, area Q21: You may indicate the diagram generally, but sign the question in neutral space away from the diagram. Q22: mean • Guidance for administering the test to pupils with a visual impairment is contained in the modified test packs. • At a pupil’s request, you may point to parts of the test paper such as charts, diagrams, statements and equations, but you must not explain the information or help the pupil by interpreting it. • The following examples illustrate how to deal with some common situations. Assistance (continued)Q. What does ‘quadrilateral’ or ‘>’ or ‘<’ mean? A. I can’t tell you, but think hard and try to remember. We can talk about it after the test. Q. What is ‘0.6’? A. That’s nought point six. • You must not explain any subject-specific terminology. If any other word in a question is unfamiliar to pupils, you may explain it, or show them objects or pictures to help  them understand . Before the test begins• Review the list of pupils with any particular individual needs, e.g. pupils who are allowed additional time, who need support from a scribe or who may need a transcript made at the end of the test. • It is important that the pupils’ names on their tests match the names on the test attendance register. Check with your test co-ordinator whether any pupil in your group is known by a different name in school, or has changed their name since pupil registration. This is so you can remind the pupil to write the correct name on their test paper. • Write the school’s name and DfE number on a board that is visible to all pupils. • Leave space on the board to write the start and finish times of the test. What to do at the start of the test• Check that seating is appropriately spaced and that no pupil can see another pupil’s test paper. • Check that pupils don’t have mobile phones or other disruptive items. • Check that pupils don’t have any materials or equipment that may give them extra help. • Ensure that each pupil has a copy of Paper 2: reasoning. • Write the start and finish times on the board so that all pupils can see them. How to introduce the testIt is important to brief pupils fully at the start of each test. You should use this script to introduce mathematics Paper 2: reasoning. This is the key stage 2 mathematics Paper 2: reasoning. You should have Paper 2: reasoning in front of you. You will need a blue or black pen, a dark sharp pencil, a ruler, a protractor and a mirror.    Write your name, school name and DfE number on the front of your test paper. [If any pupil’s name differs from the name provided during pupil registration, instruct the pupil to write both names on the paper.] Open your test paper to page 3. I will read the instructions to you. You  must not use a calculator to answer any questions in this test. You have 40 minutes to complete this test. Follow the instructions for each question.Work as quickly and as carefully as you can.If you need to do working out, you can use the space around the question. Do not write over any barcodes. Some questions have a method box. For these questions, you may get a mark for showing your method. If you cannot do a question, go on to the next one . You can come back to it later if you have time. If you finish before the end, go back and check your work. The number under each line at the side of the page tells you the number of marks available for each question. To make sure your answers can be marked, don’t write in the grey areas, on the barcode or on the lines at the top and bottom or the edge of the page and don’t crumple your test paper. If you want to change your answer, put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read. If you want to change a drawing, you should either put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read, or use a rubber. If you have to use a rubber, make sure you rub out your answer completely before writing a new one. Remember to check your work carefully. If you have any questions during the test, you should put your hand up and wait for someone to come to you. Remember, I can’t help you to answer any of the test questions. This section continues on the next page How to introduce the test (continued)You must not talk to each other. Are there any questions you want to ask me now? I will tell you when you have 5 minutes left. I will tell you when the test is over and to stop writing. You may now start the test. How to deal with issues during  the testIt is impossible to plan for every scenario. Whatever action you take, pupil safety must always be your first consideration. In the following circumstances, you will need to stop the test either for an individual pupil or for the whole cohort: • test papers are incorrectly collated or the print is illegible • an incorrect test has been administered • a fire alarm goes off • a pupil is unwell • a pupil needs to leave the room • a pupil is caught cheating. If you need to stop the test: • make a note of the time • make sure pupils are kept under test conditions and that they are supervised • if pupils have to leave the room, ensure they don’t talk about the test • speak to your test co-ordinator or a senior member of staff for advice about what to do next• consider contacting the national curriculum assessments helpline on 0300 303 3013 for further advice. You should brief your headteacher on how the incident was dealt with, once the test is over. What to do at the end  of the test• If you need to make a transcript of a test script, complete it with the individual pupil at the end of the test, under test conditions. Particular care should be taken to ensure accurate transcriptions are made and pupils’ answers are not corrected or amended. • Ensure that you inform your senior member of staff / test co-ordinator if you have made a transcript, or if a pupil has used a scribe, word processor or other electronic or technical device. This is so that they can complete the appropriate online notification. • Make sure you have collected every test script. Return them immediately to the senior member of staff who is responsible for collating the tests. • Do not look at, review or amend pupils’ answers in any way (unless it is necessary to make a transcript). If you tamper with or make changes to pupils’ answers, it will be considered maladministration and results could be annulled. • Do not keep or photocopy test scripts for any reason.• Ensure that any unused test materials are stored securely until Friday 24 May 2019.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 93,
      "year": 2019,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "copies of Paper 3: reasoningThis pack must be kept secure and unopened until the start of the test on Thursday 16 May 2019. Early opening, up to 1 hour before the test starts, is only allowed if access to the contents is needed to make adaptations to meet individual pupils’ needs. Early opening of more than 1 hour is only allowed if permission has been granted by STA. Please ensure you have read and understood the 2019 test administration guidance before opening this pack. CONFIDENTIAL",
      "answer": "– a"
    },
    {
      "id": 94,
      "year": 2019,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2019,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Key stage 2 mathematics test The key stage 2 mathematics test consists of 3 papers. The papers must be administered in order. Test packs must not be opened until the pupils are in the test room ready to complete the test, unless early opening is required to meet individual pupils’ needs. The scheduled day for the administration of Paper 3 is Thursday 16 May. Paper 3: reasoning The following information explains how to administer the key stage 2 mathematics test Paper 3: reasoning. If you have any questions, you should check with your headteacher or key stage 2 test co-ordinator before you administer the test. Please follow these instructions correctly to ensure that the test is properly administered. Failure to administer the test correctly could result in a maladministration investigation. Format • Paper 3: reasoning consists of a single test paper. • Pupils will have 40 minutes to complete Paper 3 by answering the questions in the test paper. Equipment Each pupil will need the equipment specified below: • a blue / black pen or a dark pencil • a sharp, dark pencil for mathematical drawing • a ruler (showing centimetres and millimetres) • an angle measurer or protractor (papers 2 and 3 only)• a mirror (papers 2 and 3 only). Rubbers are allowed, but please encourage pupils to cross out answers they wish to change instead of rubbing them out. Pupils may use the following equipment, if this is normal classroom practice: • monolingual English electronic spell checkers• bilingual word lists • bilingual dictionaries or electronic translators , provided they only give word-for-word translations . Pupils are not allowed: • calculators • squared paper• tracing paper. Assistance • You must ensure that nothing you say or do during the test could be interpreted as giving pupils an advantage, e.g. indicating that an answer is correct or incorrect, or suggesting the pupil looks at an answer again. • If a pupil requests it, a question may be read to the pupil on a one-to-one basis. • If reading to a pupil, you can read words and numbers but not mathematical symbols. This is to ensure that pupils are not given an unfair advantage by having the function inadvertently explained by reading its name. • For pupils with hearing impairment, be careful when signing numbers, mathematical signs and words. In particular, be careful when signing the following: Q9: You may indicate the diagram generally, but do not draw attention to the different shapes. Q10: Take care not to indicate four sides if signing quadrilateral. Q13: acute, obtuse • Guidance for administering the test to pupils with a visual impairment is contained in the modified test packs. • At a pupil’s request, you may point to parts of the test paper such as charts, diagrams, statements and equations, but you must not explain the information or help the pupil by interpreting it. • The following examples illustrate how to deal with some common situations. Q. What does ‘quadrilateral’ or ‘>’ or ‘<’ mean?  A. I can’t tell you, but think hard and try to remember. We can talk about it after the test. Q. What is ‘0.6’? A. That’s nought point six. • You must not explain any subject-specific terminology. If any other word in a question is unfamiliar to pupils, you may explain it, or show them objects or pictures to help them understand. Guidance for specific questions• Q21: The graph in this question is presented with no grid-lines. This is intentional. This is part of the demand of the question. Before the test begins• Review the list of pupils with any particular individual needs, e.g. pupils who are allowed additional time, who need support from a scribe or who may need a transcript made at the end of the test. • It is important that the pupils’ names on their tests match the names on the test attendance register. Check with your test co-ordinator whether any pupil in your group is known by a different name in school, or has changed their name since pupil registration. This is so you can remind the pupil to write the correct name on their test paper. • Write the school’s name and DfE number on a board that is visible to all pupils. • Leave space on the board to write the start and finish times of the test. What to do at the start of the test • Check that pupils don’t have mobile phones or other disruptive items. • Check that pupils don’t have any materials or equipment that may give them extra help. • Check that seating is appropriately spaced and that no pupil can see another pupil’s test paper. • Ensure that each pupil has a copy of Paper 3: reasoning. • Write the start and finish times on the board so that all pupils can see them. How to introduce the testIt is important to brief pupils fully at the start of each test. You should use this script to introduce mathematics Paper 3: reasoning. This is the key stage 2 mathematics Paper 3: reasoning. You should have Paper 3: reasoning  in front of you. You will need a blue or black pen, a dark sharp pencil, a ruler, a protractor and a mirror.    Write your name, school name and DfE number on the front of your test paper. [If any pupil’s name differs from the name provided during pupil registration, instruct the pupil to write both names on the paper.] Open your test paper to page 3. I will read the instructions to you. You must not use a calculator to answer any questions in this test.You have 40 minutes to complete this test. Follow the instructions for each question.Work as quickly and as carefully as you can.If you need to do working out, you can use the space around the question. Do not write over any barcodes.Some questions have a method box. For these questions, you may get a mark for showing your method. If you cannot do a question, go on to the next one.  You can come back to it later if you  have time. If you finish before the end, go back and check your work. The number under each line at the side of the page tells you the number of marks available for each question. To make sure your answers can be marked, don’t write in the grey areas, on the barcode or on the lines at the top and bottom or the edge of the page and don’t crumple your test paper. If you want to change your answer, put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read. If you want to change a drawing, you should either put a line through the response you don’t want the marker to read, or use a rubber. If you have to use a rubber, make sure you rub out your answer completely before writing a new one. Remember to check your work carefully. If you have any questions during the test, you should put your hand up and wait for someone to come to you. Remember, I can’t help you to answer any of the test questions. You must not talk to each other. Are there any questions you want to ask me now? I will tell you when you have 5 minutes left. I will tell you when the test is over and to stop writing. You may now start the test. How to deal with issues during the testIt is impossible to plan for every scenario. Whatever action you take, pupil safety must always be your first consideration. In the following circumstances, you will need to stop the test either for an individual pupil or for the whole cohort: • test papers are incorrectly collated or the print is illegible  (Please note that question 21 does not have grid lines drawn on the axes and this is not a printing error.) • an incorrect test has been administered • a fire alarm goes off • a pupil is unwell • a pupil needs to leave the room• a pupil is caught cheating. If you need to stop the test: • make a note of the time • make sure pupils are kept under test conditions and that they are supervised • if pupils have to leave the room, ensure they don’t talk about the test • speak to your test co-ordinator or a senior member of staff for advice about what to do next• consider contacting the national curriculum assessments helpline on 0300 303 3013 for further advice. You should brief your headteacher on how the incident was dealt with, once the test is over. What to do at the end of the test• If you need to make a transcript of a test script, complete it with the individual pupil at the end of the test, under test conditions. Particular care should be taken to ensure accurate transcriptions are made and pupils’ answers are not corrected or amended. • Ensure that you inform your senior member of staff / test co-ordinator if you have made a transcript, or if a pupil has used a scribe, word processor or other electronic or technical device. This is so that they can complete the appropriate online notification. • Make sure you have collected every test script. Return them immediately to the senior member of staff who is responsible for collating the tests. • Do not look at, review or amend pupils’ answers in any way (unless it is necessary to make a transcript). If you tamper with or make changes to pupils’ answers, it will be considered maladministration and results could be annulled. • Do not keep or photocopy test scripts for any reason.• Ensure that any unused test materials are stored securely until Friday 24 May 2019.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 95,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6,155 + 501 + 649 =",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 96,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "0 × 989 =",
      "answer": "= 25"
    },
    {
      "id": 97,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "10 +  = 302",
      "answer": "30,000 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 98,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2,400 ÷ 2 =",
      "answer": "1,200 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 99,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 70 = 485",
      "answer": "and 0.6"
    },
    {
      "id": 100,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6.48 + 8.6 =",
      "answer": "× 5"
    },
    {
      "id": 101,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 240 ÷ 8",
      "answer": "× 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 102,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "840 ÷ 5 =",
      "answer": "× 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 103,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "7,306 − 1,847 =",
      "answer": "– 1, 9, 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 104,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "1,010 × 10 =",
      "answer": "20"
    },
    {
      "id": 105,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 11,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "560 ÷ 7 =",
      "answer": "× 4 = 44"
    },
    {
      "id": 106,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 12,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6 × 10 × 11 =",
      "answer": "Masses in correct order, as shown:"
    },
    {
      "id": 107,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 13,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "1,080 ÷ 9 =",
      "answer": "120 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 108,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 14,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "500,000 − 5,000 =",
      "answer": "50 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 109,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 15,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 596 × 7",
      "answer": "4,172 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 110,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 16,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2.12 ÷ 10 =",
      "answer": "0.212 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 111,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 19,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6 0 7 × 8 3 Show your method",
      "answer": "6C7a 18 5C4 16 5F2b"
    },
    {
      "id": 112,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 23 =",
      "answer": "– 1, 9, 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 113,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 20,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "13.05 × 1,000 =",
      "answer": "+ 5 + 50 = 75"
    },
    {
      "id": 114,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 213 =",
      "answer": "30,000 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 115,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "of 30 =",
      "answer": "20"
    },
    {
      "id": 116,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 23,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "8 − 5.123 =",
      "answer": "2.877 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 117,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 2 =",
      "answer": "× 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 118,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2512,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 13 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 119,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 26,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "26 − 2.012 =",
      "answer": "23.988 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 120,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 27,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "15% of 3,200 =",
      "answer": "6R2 25 6P2"
    },
    {
      "id": 121,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 28,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2% of 3,000 =",
      "answer": "or 6.5, but the"
    },
    {
      "id": 122,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 30,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "80% of 115 =",
      "answer": "+ 44 + 34"
    },
    {
      "id": 123,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 19 =",
      "answer": "× 4"
    },
    {
      "id": 124,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 33,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "4 0 7 8 × 6 7 Show your method",
      "answer": "6C7a"
    },
    {
      "id": 125,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 23 =",
      "answer": "= 25"
    },
    {
      "id": 126,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 34,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "10 − 21",
      "answer": "6F4"
    },
    {
      "id": 127,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "=",
      "answer": "1,200 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 128,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 35,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6 + 4 ÷ 2 =",
      "answer": "− 30Answer need not be obtained for the"
    },
    {
      "id": 129,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3645,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 400 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 130,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2022,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 1: arithmetic Print version product code: STA/22/8417/p   ISBN: 978-1-78957-265-0 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/22/8417/e   ISBN: 978-1-78957-286-5 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window. They can be downloaded afterwards from https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2022 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2022 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials  You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2022 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 131,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark5N3a  Wellplaced KS2 item template version 1.2M004653  –  22 July 2019 6:07 pm – Version 2 K00070A0524 Page 6 of 24 4 Children estimated the number of beans in a jar. These were the estimates of five children. Amir 1,310 Olivia 1,220 Emma 1,400 John 1,290 Chen 1,460 The exact number of beans in the jar was 1,380 Whose estimate was closest to the exact number? Whose estimate was furthest from the exact number?1 mark",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 132,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "mark4N2a Stimator M007132  –  22 July 2019 6:09 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)K00070A0624 Page 7 of 24 5 One tonne is 1,000 kilograms. A truck can carry a load of 2.3 tonnes. How many kilograms can the truck carry? kg",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 133,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "mark5C6b  Truck load KS2 item template version 2M005810  –  22 July 2019 6:10 pm – Version 1 Emma has a 5 litre bag of compost. She uses 2.75 litres. How much compost does Emma have left? litres",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 134,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "mark6M004016  –  22 July 2019 6:11 PM – Version 10 KS2 item template version 1.14F10b  compo K00070A0724 Page 8 of 24 7 In a race, Ali completes a swim, a run and a bicycle ride. The swim is 1",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 135,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "of the total distance. The run is 3",
      "answer": "20"
    },
    {
      "id": 136,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "of the total distance. What fraction of the total distance is the bicycle ride?",
      "answer": "20"
    },
    {
      "id": 137,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "mark4F4  Triathlon KS2 item template version 2M005821  –  22 July 2019 6:12 pm – Version 3 8Circle the improper fraction that is equivalent to  23 8 5 814 819 823 826",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 138,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "1 mark5F2a  mixed up 238 KS2 item template version 2M005887  –  22 July 2019 6:14 pm – Version 2 K00070A0824 Page 9 of 24 9   This pictogram shows how many DVDs a shop sells in one week. Mon Tue Wed Thu Fri Sat On Monday, 24 DVDs were sold. How many DVDs were sold on Friday? 1 mark KS2 item template version 2M005857  –  12 November 2019 10:04 am – Version 3 3S1  DVDs graph K00070A0924 Page 10 of 24   A shop has an offer. Buy one box for £1.90 Get the second box half price. Ali buys two boxes of cereal. How much must he pay altogether? 2 marks10 Show your method £M003138  –  29 August 2019 12:30 PM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.14M9 4F10b  Cereal K00070A01024 Page 11 of 24 11 Write the missing values. 3=10 20 12=4 15 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006518  –  22 July 2019 6:18 pm – Version 2 William has four parcels. 1.4kg 1500g 2kg 300g Write the masses in order, starting with the heaviest. heaviest1 mark5M5  weightlifting 12 KS2 item template version 1.2M004752  –  12 November 2019 4:37 pm – Version 4 K00070A01124 Page 12 of 24 13 Look at the graph below that shows Dev’s bike ride.",
      "answer": "× 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 139,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 10020,
      "topic": [
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "30 4012345Distance (km) Time (minutes)B CD AE Match each part of Dev’s journey to the correct sentence. A to B Dev rests for 10 minutes. B to C Dev cycles 1km in 10 minutes. C to D Dev cycles 3km in 10 minutes. D to E Dev cycles less than 1km in 10 minutes.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 140,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark6S1  resting V2 KS2 item template version 2M005997  –  22 July 2019 6:21 pm – Version 5 K00070A01224 Page 13 of 24 14 This 850ml bottle of squash makes 17 drinks. squash 850 ml How many millilitres of squash are in each drink? ml 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006493  –  22 July 2019 6:23 pm – Version 4",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 141,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 15,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Write the correct sign =, > or < in each box.",
      "answer": "4,172 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 142,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "×  2  ×  3 1   +  2  +  3",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 143,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "×  2  ×  2 2   +  2  +  2",
      "answer": "= 25"
    },
    {
      "id": 144,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "×  10  ×  10 1  +  10  +  10",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 145,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 0,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "×  10  ×  10 0  +  10  +  10",
      "answer": "40p"
    },
    {
      "id": 146,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 971,
      "question": "marks4C6b, 3N2a  Multadd M007150  –  22 July 2019 6:24 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)K00070A01324 Page 14 of 24 16 Tick the numbers that round to 28.7 28.07 28.65 28.71 28.75 28.971 mark5F7  Decimal Rounding M007057  –  22 July 2019 6:25 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)6 divides into 40 with a remainder of 4 Write one other number that divides into 40 with a remainder of 417",
      "answer": "= 25"
    },
    {
      "id": 147,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "mark5C8a  Forti/f_ied KS2 item template version 1.2M004687  –  12 November 2019 4:40 pm – Version 2 K00070A01424 Page 15 of 24 18 This sign shows the number of empty spaces on each level of a car park at 10am. Empty Spaces 511 Level 2 268 Level 1 In this car park, each level has 800 spaces. What is the total number of cars parked in the car park at 10am? Show your method 2 marks KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006483  –  29 August 2019 12:48 pm – Version 3 K00070A01524 Page 16 of 24 The circumference of this circle is 60 centimetres. A B Not actualsize What is the distance around the edge of the circle from A to B? cm 19",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 148,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "mark6G5  smiler KS2 item template version 1.2M004789  –  12 November 2019 4:42 pm – Version 3 K00070A01624 Page 17 of 24 20   There are 432 places at a dance school. There are two age groups.This table shows the number of classes and the number of pupils in each class for each age group at the moment. Age in yearsNumber of classes Number of pupils in each class 7–12 15 16 13–18 10 18 How many more pupils can join the dance school? Show your method",
      "answer": "8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 149,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks6R4  Dance School M007072  –  29 August 2019 12:55 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)K00070A01724 Page 18 of 24   Each shape stands for a number. The total of the shapes on the diagonal line is 48The total of all the shapes is 200 Calculate the value of each shape. = =1 mark 1 mark21 KS2 item template version 2M006003  –  22 July 2019 6:39 pm – Version 5 6A4 6A1 5C6a  shape algebra K00070A01824 Page 19 of 24 You can make green paint by mixing: • 250ml of blue paint • 1,150ml of yellow paint. Stefan wants to make some of this green paint. He uses 750ml of blue paint. How much green paint does he make?22 2 marksShow your method ml6R1  greenparty KS2 item template version 2M005679  –  29 August 2019 12:27 pm – Version 6 K00070A01924 Page 20 of 24 Adam has a bag of fruit that weighs 1.25 kilograms. He takes out a banana. Now the bag of fruit weighs 1.1kg. Next, he takes out an orange. Now the bag weighs 920g. How much more does the orange weigh than the banana?23 Show your method g",
      "answer": "= 25"
    },
    {
      "id": 150,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "marks6M9 6M5  adam’s apple KS2 item template version 2M005706  –  29 August 2019 12:17 pm – Version 7 K00070A02024 Page 21 of 24 24 Here is an isosceles triangle inside a rectangle. 30º xyNot to scale Calculate the sizes of angles x and y. Show your method ° x = ° y = 2 marks KS2 item template version 2M005974  –  29 August 2019 12:15 pm – Version 4 5G4b  Tritangle K00070A02124 Page 22 of 24 25   The triangle is to be transformed on the grid as follows: • First translate the shape 7 units down.• Then reflect the resulting triangle in the y-axis. Draw the new triangle on the grid after each transformation. y x_5_7_4_3_2_1 1 2 3 4 50 _6 6 77 654321 _1 _2 _3 _4 _5 _6 _7 Use a ruler.2 marks6P2  Triangle Transformation M007113  –  22 July 2019 6:44 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)K00070A02224 Page 23 of 24 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. K00070A02324",
      "answer": "= 25"
    },
    {
      "id": 151,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2022,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 2: reasoningPrint version product code: STA/22/8418/p   ISBN: 978-1-78957-266-7Electronic PDF version product code: STA/22/8418/e   ISBN: 978-1-78957-287-2 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window. They can be downloaded afterwards fromhttps://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2022 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2022 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2022 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identi/f_ied in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 152,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Addition",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Money",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Complete the calculation. 1,000 × 416 = 10 × 1 mark K00080A01124 Page 12 of 24 Adam buys 4 pens and a ruler and pays £4.75 altogether. Jack buys 2 pens and pays £1.98 altogether. How much does a ruler  cost?10 2 marksShow your method K00080A01224 Page 13 of 24 Ally chooses a whole number. When she multiplies her number by 4, the answer is less than 100 When she multiplies her number by 5, the answer is greater than 100 Write a number that Ally could have started with.11 1 mark K00080A01324 Page 14 of 24 William says the rule for this diagram. Find the difference between the numbers in the circles. Double this to make the number in the square. 30 20 5 Use the same rule to write the missing numbers below. 100 32 400 11012 1 mark 1 mark K00080A01424 Page 15 of 2413 Write the missing fraction to make this addition  correct. 2 3  +    =  56 1 mark",
      "answer": "– 1, 9, 3"
    },
    {
      "id": 153,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 14,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Addition",
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Percentages",
        "Time",
        "Money",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Jack hires a hall for a party. This formula is used to work out the total cost. Total cost = £15 booking fee + £12.50 per hour What is the total cost of hiring the hall from 6 pm until 11 pm? £ 1 mark K00080A01524 Page 16 of 24 Stefan stands in the centre of this square. C AED B F H GNot actual size Stefan is facing towards F. He turns anti-clockwise  to face D. What angle  does Stefan turn through? degrees Stefan is now facing towards D. He turns 3 right angles clockwise . Write the letter  he faces after the turn.15 1 mark 1 mark K00080A01624 Page 17 of 2416 Part of this 10 × 10 grid is shaded. Tick the fractions that represent the shaded part of the grid. 1 4 25 4 10 6 10 40 100 2 marks K00080A01724 Page 18 of 24 17   Kim makes a cuboid model using straws. width lengthheight She uses straws that are 7.5 cm long for the height. She uses straws that are 11 cm long for the length.  She uses straws that are 8.5 cm long for the width. What is the total length of all the straws in her model? Show your method cm 2 marks K00080A01824 Page 19 of 24 18 £15 Reduced by 30% The full price of a T-shirt is £15 The price is reduced by 30%. What is the reduced price? Show your method £ 2 marks K00080A01924 Page 20 of 2419 Jack says, When you square a prime number,  the answer has only  two factors. Explain why Jack is not correct. 1 mark K00080A02024 Page 21 of 24  This table shows how many people finished the New York Marathon in each of the first four decades it was held. New York Marathon DecadeTotal number of people who finished 1st decade 24,863 2nd decade 170,9323rd decade 282,4204th decade 350,824 What is the mean number of people who finished the marathon per decade? Round your answer to the nearest hundred .20 Show your method people 3 marks K00080A02124 Page 22 of 2421 These two rectangles are identical. The length of each rectangle is three times  its width. y x(0, 1)P(–2, 8) Not to scale What are the coordinates of point P? (            ,            ) 1 mark K00080A02224 Page 23 of 24 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. K00080A02324",
      "answer": "50 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 154,
      "year": 2022,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2022,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 3: reasoningPrint version product code: STA/22/8419/p   ISBN: 978-1-78957-267-4Electronic PDF version product code: STA/22/8419/e   ISBN: 978-1-78957-288-9 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window. They can be downloaded afterwards fromhttps://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2022 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2022 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2022 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 155,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "707 − 10 =",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 156,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 6,138 + 456",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 157,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "4{ 702 =",
      "answer": "20 0.15"
    },
    {
      "id": 158,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 8,005 + 408",
      "answer": "of 60p = 15p"
    },
    {
      "id": 159,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2{ 4 { 30 =",
      "answer": "8 0.625"
    },
    {
      "id": 160,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 10 × 96",
      "answer": "300,000 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 161,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "7.8 + 6.953 =",
      "answer": "14.753 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 162,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 8,217 − 5,463",
      "answer": "×5 ÷2 20 octagon1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 163,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "450} 9 =",
      "answer": "50 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 164,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "8{ 65 =",
      "answer": "to 6"
    },
    {
      "id": 165,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 11,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2,800 ÷ 7 =",
      "answer": "400 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 166,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 12801,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "−  = 795",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 167,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 13,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2,700 ÷ 3 =",
      "answer": "9 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 168,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 59 =",
      "answer": "14.753 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 169,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 15,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "747} 9 =",
      "answer": "All four fractions correctly placed on the"
    },
    {
      "id": 170,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 17,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "0.3} 10 =",
      "answer": "0.03 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 171,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 16,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 5",
      "answer": "5 1m Refer to section 6.3 on page 16 for"
    },
    {
      "id": 172,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "=",
      "answer": "×5 ÷2 20 octagon1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 173,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1813,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 26 + 5",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 174,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 18,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "=",
      "answer": "17"
    },
    {
      "id": 175,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 19,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "29.5 − 16.125 =",
      "answer": "200 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 176,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 20,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "5 0 8 × 7 4 Show your method",
      "answer": "e.g. 65"
    },
    {
      "id": 177,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 3 =",
      "answer": "×5 ÷2 20 octagon1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 178,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 221,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 27 + 57 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 179,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 23,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "70 + 48 } 6 =",
      "answer": "78 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 180,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 24,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "3.2 × 12 =",
      "answer": "564 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 181,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 26,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "5,746 ÷ 5 =",
      "answer": "1,149 r1"
    },
    {
      "id": 182,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 27,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "52% of 700 =",
      "answer": "6R2 25b 5M9c/5M5/5F10"
    },
    {
      "id": 183,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 29,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "5 2 2 7 × 4 3 Show your method",
      "answer": "6C7a 26b 6A2/6C9"
    },
    {
      "id": 184,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks KS2 item arithmetic template version 3.0 (2019)M006112  –  6 June 2022 10:04 am – Version 1 281 3} 6 =",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 185,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 30,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "95% of 180 =",
      "answer": "6R2"
    },
    {
      "id": 186,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 31,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "0.4 × 37 =",
      "answer": "14.8 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 187,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 32,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "1 −  = 7 10",
      "answer": "3"
    },
    {
      "id": 188,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 34 =",
      "answer": "300,000 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 189,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 35,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "38% of 750 =",
      "answer": "6R2"
    },
    {
      "id": 190,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3623,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 900 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 191,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2023,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 1: arithmeticPrint version product code: STA/23/8717/p   ISBN: 978-1-78957-630-6Electronic PDF version product code: STA/23/8717/e   ISBN: 978-1-78957-651-1 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window. They can be downloaded afterwards fromhttps://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2023 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2023 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2023 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identi/f_ied in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 192,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "markM007081  –  26 April 2022 3:09 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)L00070A0424 Page 5 of 24 2 Write these temperatures in order, starting with the lowest. 6°C – 4°C 1°C –10°C 3°C °C °C °C °C °C lowest 5N5  Hot_cold",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 193,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "markM007143  –  26 April 2022 3:12 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017) L00070A0524 Page 6 of 24 3 xy 1",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 194,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "0 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 102345678910 AB CABC is a triangle. What are the coordinates of point C? (  ,  ) 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006794  –  17 February 2023 1:23 pm – Version 5 L00070A0624 Page 7 of 24 4  Some children choose their favourite zoo animal. The pictogram shows the results. Key: stands for 2 children Animal Number of children penguin elephant tiger giraffe How many more children choose tiger than elephant? 3S2 Zoo_pic",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 195,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "markM007257  –  26 April 2022 3:15 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017) L00070A0724 Page 8 of 24 5  Cars and motorbikes are parked in a street. Stefan counts 3 motorbikes and 5 cars. He counts 28 wheels altogether. Explain why Stefan cannot be correct. 1 markcar",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 196,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "wheelsmotorbike 2 wheels KS2 item template version 2M005838  –  17 February 2023 1:54 pm – Version 6 6A5  Wheels L00070A0824 Page 9 of 24 6 Kirsty buys 1 litre of apple juice for £1.39 She pays with a £5 note. How much change does Kirsty get? £ 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006593  –  26 April 2022 2:41 pm – Version 2",
      "answer": "of 60p = 15p"
    },
    {
      "id": 197,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Here is a number sequence. 75      50      25 Write the next two numbers in the sequence.1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006466  –  26 April 2022 2:32 pm – Version 2 L00070A0924 Page 10 of 24 8  In 2012, there were 24,372 schools in the United Kingdom. Round the number of schools to the nearest hundred. 4N6 4N4b  Schools In UK 1 mark KS2 item template version 1.2M004828  –  13 December 2022 12:23 pm – Version 2",
      "answer": "14.753 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 198,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Here are some diagrams showing parts of a circle. Match each diagram to the name of the dashed line. circumference diameter radius 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006606  –  6 June 2022 10:16 am – Version 2 L00070A01024 Page 11 of 24 10 Ken thinks of a number. He divides it by 3The answer is 72 What number was Ken thinking of? 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006667  –  26 April 2022 2:42 pm – Version 2",
      "answer": "50 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 199,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 11,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Write the number that is one thousand more than 19,039 Write the number that is one hundred less than 19,039 5N1  Thousand_more",
      "answer": "400 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 200,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark1 markM007137  –  26 April 2022 3:10 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017) L00070A01124 Page 12 of 24 12 Draw all the lines of symmetry on this shape. Use a ruler.4G2b  Logo_sym",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 201,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "markM007239  –  26 April 2022 3:14 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)L00070A01224 Page 13 of 24 14 Measure angle a. a is  ° a 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006786  –  17 February 2023 1:26 pm – Version 1 1",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 202,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "of a number is 22 What is the number? 135F5  fifths 1 mark KS2 item template version 2M003363  –  26 April 2022 2:22 pm – Version 2 L00070A01324 Page 14 of 24 15 Here are four fractions. 1 316 14 12 Write the fractions in the correct place on the number line. 1 0",
      "answer": "8 0.625"
    },
    {
      "id": 203,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "markM006686  –  26 April 2022 2:48 pm – Version 1 KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)L00070A01424 Page 15 of 24 16 One day last year, the rate of rainfall from 6:30 am until 9:00 am was",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 204,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "millimetres per hour. What was the total rainfall from 6:30 am until 9:00 am? mm 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006504  –  26 April 2022 2:38 pm – Version 3",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 205,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 117,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "The manager of a flower shop orders 4 boxes of red roses.  There are 50 roses in each box.  The manager makes bunches with 6 roses in each bunch. What is the greatest number of bunches that can be made? Show your method5C8b  Flower Shop",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 206,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "marksM007966  –  26 April 2022 3:27 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017) L00070A01524 Page 16 of 24 18  A cinema sells tickets at three different prices. • 1",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 207,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 20,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "of the tickets are price A. • 3",
      "answer": "e.g. 65"
    },
    {
      "id": 208,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "of the tickets are price B. • The rest of the tickets are price C. What fraction of the tickets are price C? Show your method5F4, 6F2  105_theatre_zones",
      "answer": "8 0.625"
    },
    {
      "id": 209,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "marksM007877  –  26 April 2022 3:28 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)L00070A01624 Page 17 of 24 19 Write the missing number to make this division correct. 15,000  ÷    =  75",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 210,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Percentages",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "markM006506  –  26 April 2022 2:40 pm – Version 1 KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)20 Write the two missing digits to make this long multiplication correct. 32 ×5 0 7 5 9 5 7 0 1 6 1 5 4 5 1 7 13 2 marks KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006498  –  26 April 2022 2:37 pm – Version 3 L00070A01724 Page 18 of 24 21  The height of the tallest person in history is 8 feet 11 inches. Conversion table One foot 30 centimetres One inch 2.5 centimetres Use this conversion table to calculate the height of the tallest person, in centimetres. Show your method cm 2 marks KS2 item template version 2M005843  –  28 April 2022 4:09 pm – Version 3 5M6  Tallest person L00070A01824 Page 19 of 24 22 Here is a regular hexagon. The area of the large shaded triangle is double the area of the small shaded triangle. What fraction of the whole hexagon is the shaded area? 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006679  –  26 April 2022 2:44 pm – Version 2 L00070A01924 Page 20 of 24 23  A small box contains 650 grams of cereal. A large box contains 20% more cereal.     One portion of cereal is 40 grams. How many full portions are in a large box? 650g Show your method portions6R2, 6C8  904_cereal",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 211,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "marksM007895  –  26 April 2022 3:27 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)L00070A02024 Page 21 of 24",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 212,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 124,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "1,200 pupils were asked this question: How important is it to have a break when using a screen? This chart shows the results. Not important 12% Very important Quite important 41% How many pupils answered ‘Very important’? pupils6S1  Screen Break",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 213,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "markM008048  –  17 February 2023 1:25 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017) L00070A02124 Page 22 of 24 25 There are 25 sheets of paper in a small pack. There are 500 sheets in a large pack. small",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 214,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 25,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "sheetslarge 500 sheets How many small packs make one large pack? The mass of the paper in the large pack is 2.4 kilograms. What is the mass of one sheet of paper, in grams? Show your method g",
      "answer": "6C7b 24 6S1/6R2 22 6A3/6G2a"
    },
    {
      "id": 215,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "marks1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006773  –  17 February 2023 1:22 pm – Version 2 L00070A02224 Page 23 of 24 26 This formula is used to estimate the mass (in kilograms) of young children. mass = 2 × (age in years + 5) Stefan’s sister is 4 years of age. Use the formula to estimate her mass. kg The mass of Megan’s brother is 16 kilograms. Use the formula to estimate his age. years1 mark 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006737  –  26 April 2022 2:51 pm – Version 2 L00070A02324",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 216,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2023,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 2: reasoning Print version product code: STA/23/8718/p   ISBN: 978-1-78957-631-3 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/23/8718/e   ISBN: 978-1-78957-652-8 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window.  They can be downloaded afterwards from https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2023 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2023 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials  You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2023 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 217,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Tick the number eighty thousand, three hundred and six. Tick one. 8,306 80,036 80,306 800,306 80,300,006 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006624  –  27 April 2022 2:07 pm – Version 2 L00080A0424 Page 5 of 24 3 Amina draws triangle ABC on a grid as shown. C xBAy She then reflects the triangle in the y-axis. Use a ruler.Draw the reflected triangle on the grid.1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006608  –  29 April 2022 11:02 am – Version 4 L00080A0524 Page 6 of 24 4 Write the next two numbers in this sequence. 1,780    1,880    1,9805N1  Hundred Counting",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 218,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "markM007022  –  27 April 2022 2:13 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)Circle the two decimals that round to the same whole number. 13.2  14.7  15.9  16.3  17.6 54F7  neighbours 1 mark KS2 item template version 1.2M004709  –  27 April 2022 4:04 pm – Version 2 L00080A0624 Page 7 of 24 6 Write the missing number to make the calculation correct. 1,300,450 = 1,000,000 +  + 400 + 50",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 219,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "markM006633  –  27 April 2022 2:08 pm – Version 1 KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017) Here is part of a number square. The other part of the square has been torn off. 1 21121 2122 123 4124 5 6126 7127 9129 103 121212 What number was in the bottom-left corner of the number square? 7",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 220,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "markM003156_tawny  –  27 April 2022 4:05 PM – Version 3 KS2 item template version 1.13Flc L00080A0724 Page 8 of 24 8 Match each shape to the correct name. irregular pentagon irregular hexagon regular hexagon regular pentagon 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006780  –  6 June 2022 10:35 am – Version 1 L00080A0824 Page 9 of 24  Jack says, I multiplied a whole number by 3 My answer was 32 Explain why Jack is not correct. 93C6 4C6c  multiplying 3 1 mark KS2 item template version 2M005972  –  27 April 2022 1:47 pm – Version 5 L00080A0924 Page 10 of 24",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 221,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 110,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Write the missing square number to make this addition correct.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 222,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 82,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "+ 2 = 735C5d  Add Squares",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 223,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "markM007959  –  9 January 2023 10:16 am – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)11  At the start of April, a shop had 15,000 games. The shop sold:   • 7,918 games in April • 4,624 games in May. How many games did the shop have left at the end of May? Show your method games4C4  503_consoles",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 224,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "marksM007854  –  27 April 2022 3:13 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)L00080A01024 Page 11 of 24 12  This is a drawing of a cuboid. Tick the nets that could make the cuboid.6G3 Cuboid Nets",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 225,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "marksM007106  –  27 April 2022 3:10 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017) L00080A01124 Page 12 of 24 13 Write the missing number to make this calculation correct.",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 226,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 754,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Addition",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 6  +  754 × 3  =  754 × 1 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006669  –  27 April 2022 2:11 pm – Version 3 Here are five digit cards. 1 2 3 4 5 Use two cards to make a fraction equivalent to 25% Use two cards to make a fraction equivalent to 0.414",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 227,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Decimals",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark1 markM003232  –  13 December 2022 4:22 PM – Version 5 KS2 item template version 1.15F11  equalise L00080A01224 Page 13 of 24  Amina went to a concert one evening. It took her an hour and twenty minutes to get there from home. She arrived at ten past seven. At what time did she leave home? The concert started at 7:20 pm.   It finished at 9:05 pm. How long did the concert last? hours minutes153M4d 3M4f  time traveller 1 mark1 mark KS2 item template version 2M005693  –  27 April 2022 1:41 pm – Version 5 L00080A01324 Page 14 of 24  A box of 24 chocolate eggs has a mass of 870 grams. The empty box has a mass of 30 grams. What is the mass of one chocolate egg?16 Show your method g6C7b 6C8  eggsbox 2 marks KS2 item template version 2M005652  –  27 April 2022 1:43 pm – Version 5 L00080A01424 Page 15 of 24 17  This rectangle is divided into three parts. B A CNot to scale Part A is 1",
      "answer": "4  0.25"
    },
    {
      "id": 228,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions",
        "Area",
        "Time",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "of the area of the rectangle. Part B is 13 of the area of the rectangle. What fraction of the area of the rectangle is shaded? 1 mark KS2 item template version 2M005981  –  27 April 2022 1:48 pm – Version 4 6F4, 6F11  Rectangle split L00080A01524 Page 16 of 24 18 This table shows the total rainfall and sunshine each year at Heathrow Airport from 2010 to 2015. YearRainfall in mmSunshine in hours 2010 521 1,371 2011 509 1,540 2012 700 1,503 2013 560 1,452 2014 864 1,669 2015 562 1,508 Use this table to complete the graph. Use a ruler. Rainfall in mm YearRainfall at Heathrow Airport 02004006008001,000",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 229,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2010,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Time",
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 20151,
      "question": "2011 2012 2013 2014 20151 mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006615  –  27 April 2022 2:05 pm – Version 6 L00080A01624 Page 17 of 24 Use the table to calculate the mean hours of sunshine for Heathrow Airport from 2013 to 2015. Show your method hours 2 marks KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006615  –  27 April 2022 2:05 pm – Version 2 L00080A01724 Page 18 of 24 19  These are the prices of some vegetables in a shop. Mushrooms £3.20 for 1 kgCarrots 60p for 1 kg Layla buys 500 grams of mushrooms and 1 1",
      "answer": "2011 2012 2013 2014 20151m Ignore the width of the bar."
    },
    {
      "id": 230,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "kg of carrots. She pays with a £5 note. How much change does Layla get? Show your method £5M9c, 5M9a  Veggie_Shop",
      "answer": "of 60p = 15p"
    },
    {
      "id": 231,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Addition",
        "Decimals",
        "Perimeter",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "marksM007226  –  27 April 2022 2:58 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017)L00080A01824 Page 19 of 24 20  The length of this rectangle is 6 cm. The width is w cm. w cm 6 cmNot actual size Circle all the methods below that can be used to work out the perimeter of the rectangle. w × 6 w × 2 + 12",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 232,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "+ w + 6 + w6A1, 4M7a  604_perimialg",
      "answer": "300,000 1m"
    },
    {
      "id": 233,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Percentages",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 3,
      "question": "marksM007901  –  27 April 2022 3:16 pm – Version 1 KS2 item template version 2.2 (2017) L00080A01924 Page 20 of 24 21 There are 25 classes in a school. Each class has 34 pupils.62% of all the pupils play a sport after school. What number of pupils do not play a sport? Show your method pupils 3 marks KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006555  –  27 April 2022 1:54 pm – Version 4 L00080A02024 Page 21 of 24 22 Megan uses these number machines to calculate how many diagonals different shapes have. 3 { 0 } 2 0 4 { 1 } 2 2",
      "answer": "× ( w + 6 )                    6 + w + 6 + w"
    },
    {
      "id": 234,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "{ 2 } 2 5number of vertices triangle quadrilateral pentagonnumber of diagonals Complete the number machine for the octagon. octagon6A3 4G2a  diagonal machine 1 mark KS2 item template version 2.1 (2017)M006073  –  27 April 2022 1:50 pm – Version 3 L00080A02124 Page 22 of 24 23 Write the missing decimals. One has been done for you. a ba b 1 4 0.25 3 20 5 8 2 marks KS2 item arithmetic template version 2.1 (2017)M006542  –  27 April 2022 1:52 pm – Version 2 L00080A02224 Page 23 of 24 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. L00080A02324",
      "answer": "8 0.625"
    },
    {
      "id": 235,
      "year": 2023,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2023,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 3: reasoning Print version product code: STA/23/8719/p   ISBN: 978-1-78957-632-0 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/23/8719/e   ISBN: 978-1-78957-653-5 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window.  They can be downloaded afterwards from https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2023 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials Subject to the exceptions listed below, the test materials on this website are Crown copyright and you may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2023 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exceptions – third-party copyright content in test materials  You must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, as listed in the ‘2023 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials, as listed below. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. Third-party content These materials contain no third-party copyright content. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 236,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "689 + 38 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 237,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "72 } 3 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 238,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "23 { 6 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 239,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "4,532 − 19 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 240,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "3 { 391 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 241,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 9,171 − 530",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 242,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6,600 ÷ 6 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 243,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "99 × 10 × 1 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 244,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 9,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "7.68 + 13.493 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 245,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "9 { 752 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 246,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 11,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "640 } 8 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 247,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 12,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 357 − 89",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 248,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 13,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "561 ÷ 3 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 249,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "× 18 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 250,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 15,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "= 630 ÷ 7",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 251,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 17,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2,671 × 1,000 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 252,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Addition",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark KS2 item arithmetic template version 3.0 (2019)M007420  –  10 May 2023 10:24 am – Version 1 166,020,070 = 6,000,000 +  + 70",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 253,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 12,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 1",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 254,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "=",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 255,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 3,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "+ 45 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 256,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 20,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "6 3 1 2 × 1 4 Show your method",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 257,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 21,
      "topic": [
        "Addition"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "2 + 33 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 258,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 22,
      "topic": [
        "Division",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "15.5 ÷ 100 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 259,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 23,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "90 − 56 } 8 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 260,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 25,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "4 1 8 × 4 7 Show your method",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 261,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 24,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "63 − 5.8 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 262,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 7,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 1121 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 263,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 10,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "} 2 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 264,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 28238,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 58 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 265,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 29,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "0.7 × 26 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 266,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 31,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "99% of 600 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 267,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 3 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 268,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 33,
      "topic": [
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "43% of 900 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 269,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "− 23 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 270,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "{ 39 =",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 271,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 1,
      "question_number": 2024,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Easy",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 1: arithmetic Print version product code: STA/24/8817/p     ISBN: 978-1-83507-011-6 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/24/8817/e     ISBN: 978-1-83507-032-1 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window. They can be downloaded afterwards from https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2024 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials With the exception of third-party copyright content, the 2024 key stage 2 test materials are Crown copyright. You may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information  under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2024 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exception – third-party copyright content in test materials Schools and other educational establishments, as defined in the Copyright Designs and Patents Act 1988 (CDPA), may re-use the test materials in their entirety for teaching purposes: https://www.gov.uk/guidance/exceptions-to-copyright. However, if not expressly permitted under the CDPA, you must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, listed in the ‘2024 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 272,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "The numbers in this sequence increase by the same amount each time. Write the missing numbers. –11 1 7 19 1 mark M00070A0624 Page 7 of 24 5 Write the three missing digits to make this multiplication correct. 5 ×3 72 1 mark",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 273,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 6,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Olivia is thinking of a number. My number • is greater than 236 • is less than 245 • has a 3 in the tens’ place • is an even number What number is Olivia thinking of? 1 mark M00070A0724 Page 8 of 24 7 A box holds 40 packets of envelopes. Each packet holds 25 envelopes. How many envelopes does the box hold? 1 mark",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 274,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 8,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Write a whole number in each box to make the statements correct. One has been done for you.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 275,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 18,
      "topic": [
        "Division"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "rounded to the nearest ten is  20 rounded to the nearest thousand is 4,000 rounded to the nearest ten thousand is  820,000 1 mark M00070A0824 Page 9 of 24 4 ÷ 10 40 ÷ 10",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 276,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 4,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division",
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "÷ 100 40 ÷ 100 Two of these calculations have the same answer. Write this answer as a decimal. 1 mark9 M00070A0924 Page 10 of 24 Circle the two prime numbers that have a difference of 2",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 277,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 15,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "17   19   21   23   25 1 mark10",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 278,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 11,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "This table shows the number of children and adults  at a childcare centre. Complete the table to make it correct. The first row has been done for you. Age in yearsNumber of childrenNumber of adultsNumber of children per adult",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 279,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "and under 12 4 3 2 or 3 20 4 4 or 5 3 8 1 mark M00070A01024 Page 11 of 24 12   Shapes W, X, Y and Z cover different fractions of this 10 by 10 square. W X ZY Match each shape to the correct fraction. Shape W1 100 Shape X1 4 Shape Y2 5 Shape Z1 101 mark M00070A01124 Page 12 of 24 14  A class votes for a captain. Three-quarters of the class vote for Sam.   The remaining 7 pupils vote for Alex. How many pupils are in the class?",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 280,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Subtraction",
        "Decimals",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark13 Match the name of each 3-D shape to its number of vertices. cube 9 square-based pyramid 8 triangular-based prism 6 octagonal-based pyramid 5 1 mark M00070A01224 Page 13 of 24 15 Write the missing number to make this multiplication correct. 3.207  ×  100  =    ×  10 1 mark",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 281,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 16,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals",
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "Here is a number. 9,658,214 Tick the statements that are true. The digit 5 represents 50,000 The value of the digit 9 is nine hundred thousands. The digit 6 represents 6 millions. The value of the digit 2 is twenty tens.2 marks M00070A01324 Page 14 of 24 17 Chen buys these four items. 670 grams £1.50400 grams £0.70500 grams 750 grams £1.45 Chen pays for the four items with a £ 10 note. The price of the butter is not shown. She receives £3.85 change. What is the price of the butter? Show your method £ 2 marks M00070A01424 Page 15 of 24 Draw an arrow (  ) on the scale below to show 1350 grams. 1.5 1 2 kilograms 1 mark18",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 282,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 19,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Percentages",
        "Time"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "A hall has 1,250 seats. At 7 pm, 880 seats are filled.At 8 pm, there are 40 empty seats. How many seats were filled between 7 pm and 8 pm? Show your method seats 2 marks M00070A01524 Page 16 of 24 20   Each day, a school has • break from 10:15 am to 10:30 am • lunchtime from 12:40 pm to 1:30 pm. What is the total time the school has for breaks and lunchtime in a 5-day week? Show your method hours   minutes 2 marks M00070A01624 Page 17 of 24 21 Tick all the correct statements. AB is parallel to CD GH is parallel to AB CD is perpendicular to GH EF is perpendicular to CD A GC DE FB H 1 mark M00070A01724 Page 18 of 24   This table shows the distance that five friends travel to school each day. Name Distance (km) Amina 1.8 William 2.4 Layla 3.2 Chen 1.6 Dev 4.5 What is the mean distance they travel to school each day? Show your method km 2 marks22 M00070A01824 Page 19 of 24 23  Mrs Mills has 940 seeds to plant into trays. She plants 12 seeds in each tray. The last tray is not full. What fraction of the last tray is filled? Show your method 2 marks M00070A01924 Page 20 of 24  Here are four numbers. 40 60 64 100 Use each number once to complete these statements. is a square number. is a cube number. is a common multiple of 4 and 5 is a common factor of 80 and 120 2 marks24 M00070A02024 Page 21 of 24 25 Write the missing numbers so that 3 × b – a = 2 ab 2 13 2 marks Here are 3 translations on a coordinate grid. Tick the translations that are four units to the left. from (0, 2) to (4, 2) from (6, 8) to (2, 8) from (–3, 5) to (–7, 5)1 mark26 M00070A02124 Page 22 of 24 27   Olivia has two jars of beads. The number of beads in Jar A is double the number of beads in Jar B. Beads Jar A Jar B Beads Olivia says, 25% of the number of beads in Jar A is the same as 50% of the number of beads in Jar B. Explain why Olivia is correct. 1 mark M00070A02224 Page 23 of 24 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. M00070A02324",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 283,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 2,
      "question_number": 2024,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 2: reasoning Print version product code: STA/24/8818/p     ISBN: 978-1-83507-012-3 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/24/8818/e     ISBN: 978-1-83507-033-8 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window.  They can be downloaded afterwards from https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2024 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials With the exception of third-party copyright content, the 2024 key stage 2 test materials are Crown copyright.  You may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information  under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2024 national curriculum assessments and licensed under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exception – third-party copyright content in test materials Schools and other educational establishments, as defined in the Copyright Designs and Patents Act 1988 (CDPA), may re-use the test materials in their entirety for teaching purposes: https://www.gov.uk/guidance/exceptions-to-copyright. However, if not expressly permitted under the CDPA, you must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, listed in the ‘2024 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material.   . If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 284,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Long Division",
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Perimeter",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Match each of these Roman numerals to the correct number. One has been done for you. CVI 1110 DXC 106 DLXXI 590 MCX 571 1 mark M00080A0724 Page 8 of 24 6 Match each fraction to its equivalent simplified fraction. One has been done for you. Fraction Simplified fraction 12 2045 1215 23 1216 35 1218 34 1 mark M00080A0824 Page 9 of 24 7   Emma thinks of a number. She says, ൺ multiply by 2 ൺ add 11 ൺ divide by 3 My answer is 9 What number did Emma think of? 1 mark M00080A0924 Page 10 of 24 8  Here is a shape. Draw the shape after it is translated 8 units to the right. y x8 76543210 1234567_5_6_7_4_3_2_1 0 Use a ruler.1 mark M00080A01024 Page 11 of 24 9 Write the missing numbers in the table. Number of weeksNumber of days 17 21 4 42 8 6 10 105 1 mark M00080A01124 Page 12 of 24 10 What is the perimeter of the shape, in millimetres? Use a ruler. Measure the size of angle  d. Use an angle measurer. d is °ABC D mm 1 mark dABC D 1 mark M00080A01224 Page 13 of 24 11 Write the missing digits to make this subtraction correct. 57 –3 5 68 2 marks",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 285,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 12,
      "topic": [
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals",
        "Percentages"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "Here are four fractions. 7 815 34 8 10 Write the fractions in order starting with the least. least1 mark M00080A01324 Page 14 of 24 13   There are 20 boxes on a truck. The boxes are in 4 different sizes. 6 of these boxes2 of these boxes8 of these boxes 4 of these boxes4kg 13kg 6.5kg2.5kg What is the total mass of the 20 boxes on the truck? 2 marksShow your method kg M00080A01424 Page 15 of 24 14  Look at the data in this table. Label Percentage A 20% B 25% C 15% D 30% E 10% Using this data, draw two lines and write three labels to complete the pie chart. Use a ruler. A B 2 marks M00080A01524 Page 16 of 24 15   35% of the 680 pupils at a school have a pet dog.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 286,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 159,
      "topic": [
        "General"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "of the pupils who have a pet dog are boys. How many of the pupils who have a pet dog are girls? 2 marksShow your method M00080A01624 Page 17 of 24 16 Write a number in the box to make this correct. 3",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 287,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 5,
      "topic": [
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1001,
      "question": "<        <    0.7 1001 mark",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 288,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 17,
      "topic": [
        "Money",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 91,
      "question": "Tick the numbers that are factors of both 54 and 72 2 3 4 8 91 mark M00080A01724 Page 18 of 24  Layla wants to buy a camera that costs £65 For the first 10 weeks, she saves £2 each week. Then she saves £3 each week. How many weeks altogether does it take Layla to save £65? Show your method weeks18 2 marks M00080A01824 Page 19 of 24 20 Here are four shapes on a grid. A B C D Write the letters of all the shapes that have only two acute angles.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 289,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Long Multiplication",
        "Addition",
        "Subtraction",
        "Money"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "mark19 Complete this division. 64 r1 12 4 3 6 2 marks M00080A01924 Page 20 of 24 21   A band holds a concert for charity. The tickets cost £27 each.  They sell 635 tickets.  They pay £3,180 to use the hall.  They give one-third of the remaining amount to charity. How much money does the band give to charity? 3 marksShow your method £ M00080A02024 Page 21 of 24 22  Sarah makes jewellery using black and white beads. She uses this rule to work out how many black beads to use. black = (white × 3) + 4 Sarah uses 12 white beads to make a necklace. How many black beads does she use? Sarah uses 25 black beads to make a bracelet. How many white beads does she use? 1 mark 1 mark M00080A02124 Page 22 of 24 241",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 290,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2,
      "topic": [
        "Multiplication"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "×  56  is greater than the value of  13  ×  78 Explain how you know.",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 291,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 1,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Geometry"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Hard",
      "marks": 1,
      "question": "mark23 Complete the table. Name of 3-D shape Number of faces cube pentagonal prismtriangular-based pyramid 1 mark M00080A02224 Page 23 of 24 [END OF TEST] Please do not write on this page. M00080A02324",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    },
    {
      "id": 292,
      "year": 2024,
      "paper": 3,
      "question_number": 2024,
      "topic": [
        "Subtraction",
        "Fractions",
        "Decimals"
      ],
      "difficulty": "Medium",
      "marks": 2,
      "question": "key stage 2 mathematics Paper 3: reasoning Print version product code: STA/24/8819/p     ISBN: 978-1-83507-013-0 Electronic PDF version product code: STA/24/8819/e     ISBN: 978-1-83507-034-5 For more copies Additional copies of this book are not available during the test window.  They can be downloaded afterwards from https://www.gov.uk/government/collections/national-curriculum-assessments-practice-materials. © Crown copyright 2024 Re-use of Crown copyright in test materials With the exception of third-party copyright content, the 2024 key stage 2 test materials are Crown copyright.  You may re-use them (not including logos) free of charge in any format or medium in accordance with the terms of the Open Government Licence v3.0 which can be found on the National Archives website and accessed via the following link: www.nationalarchives.gov.uk/doc/open-government-licence. When you use this information  under the Open Government Licence v3.0, you should include the following attribution: ‘Contains material developed by the Standards and Testing Agency for 2024 national curriculum assessments and licensed  under Open Government Licence v3.0’ and where possible provide a link to the licence. Exception – third-party copyright content in test materials Schools and other educational establishments, as defined in the Copyright Designs and Patents Act 1988 (CDPA), may re-use the test materials in their entirety for teaching purposes: https://www.gov.uk/guidance/exceptions-to-copyright. However, if not expressly permitted under the CDPA, you must obtain permission from the relevant copyright owners, listed in the ‘2024 key stage 2 tests copyright report’, for re-use of any third-party copyright content which we have identified in the test materials. Alternatively, you should remove the unlicensed third-party copyright content and/or replace it with appropriately licensed material. If you have any queries regarding these test materials, contact the national curriculum assessments helpline on",
      "answer": "NEEDS_ANSWER"
    }
  ]
}